<Document>
# Blob

[color=#ff0000]A level five biological threat was detected at the station, and the isolation of the station was announced.[/color]

A blob is a fast-growing dangerous organism whose main goal is to take over the station.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CoreBlobTile" Caption="Blob"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobMouseCancer" Caption="Carrier of the blob"/>
  </Box>

You can become a blob carrier both at the beginning of the round and in the middle if you take on the role of a ghost. Usually, the carrier of the blob is a sentient humanoid, or a special green radioactive mouse.

## Nucleus

The most important blob cell is [color=#a4885c]nucleus[/color]. By destroying the nucleus, the blob will be defeated, and all its other cells will die.

You can always see the core health on the right side of the screen as a percentage. Watch your core and don't let it be destroyed!

There are 2 steps you can do with the kernel: [color=#a4885c]transfer[/color] and [color=#a4885c]split[/color].
- When a kernel is transferred, the selected node and kernel are swapped. This is useful in case the kernel location is not very secure.
- When the kernel is split, the selected node becomes [color=#a4885c]new and independent kernel[/color]. Although this action requires a lot of points, in the long run, a new core can help you capture the station.

## Blob Types

Your ordinary unity is a [bold]regular tile[/bold]. Normal cells are extremely vulnerable to burns or even mechanical damage.
They can also be upgraded to reinforced versions, or turned into special blob Tiles.

## Special cages

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ResourceBlobTile" Caption="Resource Blob"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FactoryBlobTile" Caption="Factory Blob"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NodeBlobTile" Caption="Node Blob"/>
  </Box>

- [color=#a4885c]The Resource Blob[/color] is constantly gaining points for all the actions the blob performs.
- [color=#a4885c]Blob Factory[/color] creates Blob Pods and Blobburnouts to help fight against the station.
- [color=#a4885c]Blob node[/color] allows you to place other blob cells around it within a certain radius.

Note! Special blob cells are tied to the nearest core.
Thus, for the best placement, you should place the nodes as compactly as possible, and build other special cells around them.

When a node is destroyed, all bound special tiles are destroyed with the return of their value.

## Minions

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobBlobBlobbernaut" Caption="Blobbernaut"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobBlobPod" Caption="Blob Pod"/>
  </Box>

Blob factories can produce Blob pods and Blobburnouts.
- Blob pods have the ability to turn dead humanoids into zombie blobs, which will force them to fight on your side against the rest of the crew.
- Blobburnouts have a lot of damage, which will come in handy for attacking.

## Management

- To place a blob cage, click on an empty space. If a tile is occupied, or someone or something is standing on it, clicking on it will attack and deal damage.
- Note that [color=#a4885c]you cannot place regular blob cages far from blob nodes. Put blob knots to be able to grow further.
- By pressing Alt+LMB, you can upgrade normal tiles to sturdy and sturdy tiles to reflective.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StrongBlobTile" Caption="Strong tiles"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ReflectiveBlobTile" Caption="Reflective tiles"/>
  </Box>

## Special Abilities

In the action bar, you can use special abilities that will allow you to perform important actions, such as placing special cells, or special actions with the core and chemicals.

- [color=#a4885c]Changing a chemical[/color] allows you to change your chemical to any of the 5 presented. Each has its own characteristics suitable for different situations.
- [color=#a4885c]Demote Blob[/color] gives you the option to downgrade any blob cell back to normal for free. It is useful in order to correct the wrong placement.

## Course of the round

As the blob grows, the station will pass through several stages.

- 1. [color=#a4885c]Silent stage[/color] - the blob is still undetected, and you can safely evolve while no one knows about you.
- 2. [color=#a4885c]Threat detection[/color] - as soon as the blob grows a little, a Sigma code is installed and a complete isolation of the station is declared. The evacuation shuttle cannot be called at this point.
- 3. [color=#a4885c]Critical mass[/color] - if a blob captures a significant part of the station, a gamma code is announced and a CBRN squad arrives to help. The main goal of all survivors at this stage is to blow up the station, which you as a blob must prevent! (note CBRN currently now aveilable)
- 4. [color=#a4885c]Blob Win[/color] - When a blob grows to a gigantic size, its growth becomes too uncontrollable, causing the round to end with the blob winning.

Starting from the second stage, the captain has a priority goal in the form of protecting the nuclear authentication disk. If you lose it, the blob cannot be destroyed in the Gamma code, which gives an almost guaranteed victory to the blob!

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NukeDisk" Caption="Nuclear Authentication Disk"/>
  </Box>

## Methods of control

Since the blob is a biological creature, [color=#ff5500]heat and burning[/color] are the blob's main weaknesses. Burn damage is extremely effective against it, so the following weapons can help you:

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MagazineBoxPistolIncendiary" Caption="Incendiary Rounds"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponLaserCarbine" Caption="Laser Rifle"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Welder" Caption="Welder "/>
  </Box>

</Document>
