<Document>
  # Revenant

  A Revenant is a telekinetically controlled corpse used by the Harbinger to temporarily gain a physical body. This is your peak form, a short burst of overwhelming power that lets you turn the station into a disaster zone.

  Once you possess a corpse, you lose access to your usual wraith powers and instead gain a limited but much more destructive arsenal. You regenerate WP faster, but your health constantly drains and cannot be healed. When your time runs out, the body collapses into smoke and your spirit returns to the void.

  Revenants are visually distinct, surrounded by a dark, swirling aura. When one appears, the station knows something terrible has happened.

  ## Push

  - Shoves the targeted victim or object away with telekinetic force.
  - Deals damage if the target hits a wall or another object.
  - Useful for knocking enemies into hazards or clearing space in tight areas.

  ## Mass Command

  - Launches every nearby loose object toward a target at once. It's basically the base command action, but on steroids.
  - Devastating in cluttered rooms like cargo or chemistry. The more sharp objects nearby, the better.

  ## Shockwave

  - Releases a massive blast of telekinetic energy that knocks everyone down, shatters windows, and rips plating off floors and walls.
  - Can be used to disable entire rooms, breach areas, or make quick escapes.

  ## Touch of Evil

  - Temporarily supercharges your physical attacks.
  - Your punches deal enormous damage and send targets flying across the room.

  ## Crush

  - Focuses your full telekinetic might on a single target, slowly pulverizing them.
  - Deals immense brute damage over time until the target explodes into gibs.
  - The effect ends if you lose line of sight or are interrupted.
  - Is extremely expensive to use, so make sure you don't waste it.

  ### General Tips

  Revenant form is temporary, make every second count. You’re not here to survive; you’re here to devastate.

  Use Shockwave first to scatter and disarm the crew, then pick off survivors with Touch of Evil or Crush.

  Push and Mass Command can both be used to clear barricades or fling objects at fleeing crew.

  Though the revenant has access to terrifying skills, the vessel is still mortal. Don't expect to just tank a bunch of bullets for no reason and make it out alive.

  Remember: once you die, you return to your wraith form. Don’t waste time trying to retreat, just go ham.

  [textlink="Back to Harbinger of the Void" link="Harbinger"]
</Document>
