<Document>
# Slasher

[color=#ac3a0d]An unstoppable 80's terror driven by vengeance, dread, and synth beats echoing through dark maintenance.[/color]

The Slasher is a relentless horror that stalks isolated crew, harvesting their souls and growing stronger with every victim. It thrives on fear, appearing and vanishing between flickers of light and fresh trails of blood.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHatSlasherMask" Caption="Mask"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SlasherMachete" Caption="Machete"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SlasherMeatSpike" Caption="Meat Spike"/>
</Box>

  Unlike most midround antagonists the slasher starts off weak. For every soul they steal they gain that much more strength. If left unchecked they can quickly become a terrifying force.

  ## Core Loop
  1. Find isolated targets.

  2. Incapacitate and absorb their soul.

  3. Repeat.

  4. Once you reach 15 souls, an announcement warns the crew of your ascendance.

  ## Abilities

<Box>
  [tex path="_Goobstation/Actions/slashericons.rsi" state="SummonMachete" scale="2"/]
  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    ## Summon Machete

You can always call your signature weapon back to your active hand. If it's been destroyed, this will create a new one. Great for recovering your weapon or throwing it for quick damage.

[italic]Cooldown: 20 seconds.[/italic]
  </Box>
</Box>

<Box>
  [tex path="_Goobstation/Actions/slashericons.rsi" state="SoulSteal" scale="2"/]
  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    ## Soul Steal

Can only be used on an incapacitated or restrained target within close range. For every soul stolen, you gain increased damage on your machete and armor. Living victims provide much greater bonuses than corpses. Victims become [italic]soulless[/italic] and receive a random negative devil clause. Releases a cloud of ammonia gas on success.

[italic]Cooldown: 2 seconds. Do-after time: 15 seconds.[/italic]

  - Living souls: +1.5 slash damage, +5% armor per soul
  - Dead souls: +0.75 slash damage, +2.5% armor per soul
  - Maximum armor: 70% damage reduction
  - Unlocks [bold]Possession[/bold] after stealing 10 souls
  - Triggers [bold]Ascendance[/bold] at 15 total souls (station-wide announcement)
  - After ascending, lights periodically flicker and break around you
  </Box>
</Box>

<Box>
  [tex path="_Goobstation/Actions/slashericons.rsi" state="RelentlessGrab" scale="2"/]
  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    ## Relentless Grab

When activated, your next punch will instantly hard-grab your target. Perfect for securing your targets onto your meatspikes.

[italic]Cooldown: 15 seconds.[/italic]
  </Box>
</Box>

<Box>
  [tex path="_Goobstation/Actions/slashericons.rsi" state="SummonMachete" scale="2"/]
  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    ## Massacre

An incredibly powerful attack mode tied to your machete. Activating this makes it so consecutive hits on the same humanoid target build a stronger combo the more you hit them:

  - When activated it applies a damage penalty (-9 damage) and disables wideswings
  - Each consecutive hit adds bonus damage (+3 per hit)
  - Every 4th hit severs a random limb (arm or leg)
  - The 13th consecutive hit decapitates your victim
  - Missing or switching targets resets the combo
  - Killing a victim with massacre grants a temporary speed boost and healing (scales with hit count)
  - Chain ends automatically if 10 seconds pass without landing a hit

[italic]Cooldown: 20 seconds.[/italic]
  </Box>
</Box>

<Box>
  [tex path="_Goobstation/Actions/slashericons.rsi" state="Regenerate" scale="2"/]
  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    ## Regeneration

An incredibly robust source of healing. Instantly rejuvenates you, removes all restraints, and cures all wounds. After every use you must recharge it by stealing another soul. Can be used while dead.

[italic]Cooldown: 75 seconds.[/italic]
  </Box>
</Box>

<Box>
  [tex path="_Goobstation/Actions/slashericons.rsi" state="BloodTrail" scale="2"/]
  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    ## Blood Trail

Toggle to leave a trail of blood in your wake while playing some funky music. Spooky!

[italic]No cooldown (toggle).[/italic]
  </Box>
</Box>

<Box>
  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    <Box>
      [tex path="_Goobstation/Actions/slashericons.rsi" state="Incorporealize" scale="2"/]
    </Box>
    <Box>
      [tex path="_Goobstation/Actions/slashericons.rsi" state="Corporealize" scale="2"/]
    </Box>
  </Box>
  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    ## Incorporeal / Corporealization

Your main traversal ability. Become incorporeal to phase through walls and become invisible while being unable to interact with anything. You can only enter this form when completely unseen. if anyone has line of sight to you, you cannot incorporealize. Similarly, you cannot exit incorporeal form if a camera can see your destination or if someone is nearby.

[italic]Incorporeal do-after: 5 seconds. No cooldown (Toggle).[/italic]

  - All ability cooldowns are frozen while incorporeal. They will not continue until you return to your physical form.
  - Disables nearby lights (5 tile radius) when entering
  - An alert shows whether you're currently being observed
  </Box>
</Box>

<Box>
  [tex path="_Goobstation/Actions/slashericons.rsi" state="Possession" scale="2"/]
  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    ## Possession

Unlocked after stealing 10 souls. Temporarily take control of a victim's body for 45 seconds. When the duration ends or you cancel early, both minds return to their original bodies. Mindshields and tinfoil hats block this ability.

[italic]Cooldown: 180 seconds (3 minutes).[/italic]
  </Box>
</Box>

<Box>
  [tex path="_Goobstation/Actions/slashericons.rsi" state="Meatspike" scale="2"/]
  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    ## Meat Spike

Instantly summon an Ominious Meat Spike at your current position. Victims who get buckled to it become trapped, making them easy targets for soul steal.

[italic]Cooldown: 15 seconds.[/italic]
  </Box>
</Box>

<Box>
  [tex path="_Goobstation/Actions/slashericons.rsi" state="StaggerArea" scale="2"/]
  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    ## Stagger Area

Release a wave of terror in a 3.5 tile radius around you, slowing all nearby enemies by 50% for 8 seconds. Very useful for catching fleeing victims.

[italic]Cooldown: 20 seconds.[/italic]
  </Box>
</Box>

<Box>
  [tex path="_Goobstation/Actions/slashericons.rsi" state="SlasherVision" scale="2"/]
  <Box Orientation="Vertical">
    ## Enhanced Vision

Toggleable night vision that allows you to see perfectly in darkness with a red tint.

[italic]No cooldown (toggle).[/italic]
  </Box>
</Box>

  ## Crew Tips
  [bold]Do not wander alone.[/bold]
  - The Slasher is relatively weak when first appearing on station.
  - As they steal souls, they become significantly tankier and deal much more damage.
  - If you spot them, keep them in sight. they cannot escape to incorporeal form while observed.
  - They are weak to holy damage. Coordinate with the chaplain if available.
  - Tinfoil hats and mindshields prevent possession.
  - Upon 15 souls stolen, an announcement warns the crew of their ascendance.
  - Cameras can prevent them from exiting incorporeal form.
  - Their cooldowns freeze while incorporeal.
  - Group up and travel with others. the Slasher excels at picking off isolated targets.
  - If they hard grab you and attempt to put you on a meatspike you can cancel it by shoving them.
  - They cannot use guns.
  - They have no critical state. They're either alive or dead.

  [color=red][bold]You are the legend of the midnight massacre. make it feel like one.[/bold][/color]
</Document>
