<Document>
 # Security Duty Weapons

  ## Foreword
  While firearms of all varieties are incredibly common across known-space, the NanoTrasen Corporation does not permit
  individuals without proper licenses to carry weapons onboard its stations. [color=#a40000]Carrying any weapon on NanoTrasen property
  without proper authorization is a crime.[/color] The following job positions are assumed to be properly licensed and permitted to be armed:

  - [color=#a40000]All Security personnel[/color]: without any restrictions.
  - [color=#4169e1]All NanoTrasen command staff[/color]: without any restrictions.
  - [color=#228b22]Bartending personnel[/color]: Limited only to long-arms such as rifles and shotguns. Additionally, they may only be equipped with less-than-lethal ammunition.
  - [color=#e2725b]Salvage personnel[/color]: Lethal weapons usage is permitted for those whom are expected to perform tasks that involve significant risk to life and
    limb, such as ship breaking or planetary expeditions.

  ## What are Duty Weapons?

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponPistolMk58Security" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponDisabler" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Truncheon" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Security characters are classified as Private Armed Security. As Private Armed Security,
  they are entitled via special training and licensing to be equipped with lethal weaponry in their daily work.
  Such weapons serve the purpose of protecting corporate assets, such as the Station or its Crew.

  This key piece of job equipment, typically a handgun of some variety, is called a "Duty Weapon" when used in the context of armed security work.
  Duty Weapons are usually issued to the officer by their employer directly, but are not necessarily ones provided by the corporation.
  In order to save money on equipping their station security, corporations typically allow security staff to buy appropriate firearms using their own paycheck.

  Any firearm that is listed without cost may be assumed to be provided by NanoTrasen directly. However for Duty Weapons that cost loadout points,
  the assumption is different. These weapons are assumed to be owned by the security officer themself, and thus are a private possession of that
  individual which was bought using their hard-earned paycheck.

  ## Why does this list include weapons typically used by Syndicate agents?

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponRevolverPythonSecurity" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponPistolViperSecurity" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponPistolN1984Security" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Across known-space, there exist many corporations both large and small whom manufacture firearms for the consumer markets. A majority of all firearms
  on the market are generic models that can be produced by anyone with the right equipment. As a result, the universe is full of weapons whose origin cannot
  be readily traced to any one particular corporation. Companies like NanoTrasen will typically establish business deals with some manufacturers to supply their
  security forces, but nothing compares to the cost savings that can be found by letting private security buy their own weapons.

  Firearms like the Mk58 are incredibly popular with corporations like NanoTrasen due to their astoundingly low cost.
  Yet, the Mk58 is often reviled by security workers all across known-space. When given a choice, security workers will likely purchase
  firearms that they actually like, or are more desirable to carry in their day-to-day work. Weapons such as the Viper may be used as a relatively
  affordable option for officers looking to pack just a little bit more punch. Revolvers such as the Python are incredibly popular with security workers,
  especially those that have a large and intimidating frame.

</Document>
