<Document>
# Psionics
[color=#a4885c]Psionics[/color] are mental abilities that interface with the [color=#a4885c]noösphere[/color]. Humans have limited access to the noösphere's full potential, allowing some to find ways to command it.
The abilities originate from distorting a noöspheric imprint into a specific shape, a bit like a lock and key. Having powers is like possessing a ring of keys, with each key granting one ability.
Barring unusual circumstances, most psychics will only possess a single power, but there are hidden ways to obtain more.

## Power Scaling
The relative strength of a psychic entity is given as two measurements, [color=#ff4500]Amplification (kα)[/color], and [color=#87cefa]Dampening (kδ)[/color]. [color=#ff4500]Amplification[/color] is a measure of
how forcefully an entity can manipulate the noösphere, bending its currents to their will. A Pyromancer with high Amplification can throw a deadlier firebolt, but the noösphere will respond in kind with a
proportionally greater increase in Glimmer. [color=#87cefa]Dampening[/color] by contrast is a measure of how controlled an entity is with their powers. With some exceptions, Dampening directly decreases
the amount of Glimmer generated by casting powers.

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobIfritFamiliar" />
Many other creatures can have power scaling different from that of a human, and thus may interact with their powers in ways different from an equivalent humanoid psion. To give an example, an Ifrit will usually have
five times as much Amplification as the baseline, causing their Pyromancy to be substantially more dangerous than that of a human Pyromancer.

## Psionic Potential
Not all individuals have the ability to become Psionic. Individuals who can are known as Latents. This is given by the Latent Psychic Trait that must be taken at character creation. Without said trait, an individual
may never become a psychic at any point in the round. There are extraordinarily rare exceptions to this rule, but none are known publicly. Latents have innate access to a minor form of Telepathy, which is
identical to that provided temporarily by powerful hallucinogens, as well as intense states of dreaming. They cannot speak Telepathically, however, until they have obtained the Telepathy power.

## Telepathy
Nearly all forms of Psionic Powers also come with a secondary power called [color=#32cd32]Telepathy[/color], which works like a sort of noöspheric radio channel shared by all those who have psionic potential.
Telepathy is accessed by starting a message with the = sign. Telepathy requires that the user be alive and conscious, but is not inhibited by most sources of muteness.
It is notable that all Telepathic messages are fully anonymous, and are not guaranteed to come from a human being. Woe befalls the fool who blindly trusts what he hears telepathically.

Not all Psionic entities have Telepathy, but most do.

## Glimmer
[color=#a4885c]Glimmer[/color] is a more colloquial term for [color=#a4885c]noöspheric pressure[/color], measured in [color=#a4885c]milli-Psi (mΨ)[/color]. The noösphere can be considered analogous to a pool of still,
onyx black water. The waters have an inherent desire for stillness, for law, for an order of all things. The usage of psychic powers is like throwing a rock into the pool, creating waves that can be measured. As the waves
build up, primordial chaos can potentially enter through our realm through areas where the pool is at its thinnest. While exceptions exist, the psychic powers generally follow Gunderaan's First Law when increasing
Glimmer. Thus, Glimmer increases are given by the formula:

ΔΨ = ~0.006 * kα - kδ

Verbally, this law is read as, "Change in Glimmer is equal to approximately six milli-Psi times Amplification, minus Dampening."

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SophicScribe" />
The [color=#a4885c]sophic scribe[/color] tracks glimmer.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GlimmerProber"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GlimmerDrain"/>
</Box>

Epistemics can build devices to interact with glimmer. These are usually the main determiners of where glimmer is going.
[color=#a4885c]Glimmer probers[/color] will increase glimmer, but directly generate research points without further input. [color=#a4885c]Glimmer drains[/color] simply drain glimmer at the cost of electricity.

Use of psionics will increase glimmer, as will [color=#a4885c]noöspheric storms[/color].

## Discharges
Glimmer will occasionally discharge if it's above 100 mΨ, causing a wide range of effects based on just how high it is. The most common is giving all entities with psionic potential a small seizure,
which is something most people working on stations with an Epistemics department have grown used to.

## Acquiring Psionics
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Oracle" />

First, an individual must be a Latent Psychic. Without the Potential for powers, an individual can never in their life obtain psionic abilities. All Latent Psychics start with a
baseline 10% chance to start each round with a random psychic power. Some particular individuals may have a higher baseline chance. After this initial chance, individuals may obtain
powers during a round by certain acts, such as consuming large quantities of hallucinogenic drugs. When this happens, the local Glimmer also acts as a way of increasing the chances of
obtaining powers. Each individual has "One Free Reroll" of their powers, so use it wisely.

The odds of obtaining powers via drug consumption are given by Gunderaan's Second Law:

χ = (10 + 0.001Ψ + φ) * ψ

Where χ is the percentage chance of obtaining powers, Ψ is the glimmer present during the roll, φ is the potential bonus chance some individuals may possess, and ψ is the potential multiplier
that a given hallucinogen may have. Not all hallucinogens have the same chance of granting powers. Most famously, Lotophagic Oil multiplies a user's chances of obtaining powers by 4. Some individuals may also have
an innate potential multiplier, such as the station's Chaplain.

## Psionic Insulation
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadTinfoil"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHelmetInsulated"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PillCryptobiolin" />
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadCage" />
</Box>
Psionic Insulation is a catch-all term for any source of protection from mind-affecting psionic powers, as well as some noöspheric discharges. It is most commonly obtained from wearing special
protective headgear, or from drugs such as Cryptobiolin that render one temporarily protected. Some entities can be innately insulated, such as nearly all forms of synthetic life, though
exceptions may exist. Rarer still, some humanoids may be born with an innate psionic insulation.

## Handling Glimmer Emergencies
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GlimmerProber"/>
Probers should be turned off before glimmer exceeds 500 mΨ.

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GlimmerDrain"/>
Glimmer drains are quite effective at draining glimmer, taking it out as fast as a prober can put it in.

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Ectoplasm" />
[color=#a4885c]Ectoplasm[/color], combined in a beaker with equal parts water, ash, blood, and plasma, will produce a normality crystal when heated enough. [color=#fcdf03]Use a hot plate for this.[/color]
Ectoplasm is needed for the construction of Glimmer Drains, and is a very rare substance that can only be obtained from noöspheric entities.

## Mind Breaking
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PillMindbreakerToxin" />
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShellSoulbreaker" />
</Box>

Mind Breaking is the act of permanently destroyed an individual's link to the noösphere, and as such is considered by space law to be an act equivalent to Murder. It is NOT the job of any individual
on the station to go about mind breaking all psionics, such a thing must not be taken likely, and should only be performed under extreme circumstances. Once mind broken, an individual loses an essential
spark of humanity, making it so that for the rest of their natural life, they can never again be a psychic.

Mind Breaking is performed by either imbibing a pill of Mindbreaker Toxin, or an injection of Soulbreaker. It is to be performed only as an emergency measure during a Code White situation, and only with
the permission of the station's Commanding Officer. Mind Breaking may also be given by the station's Commanding Officer as a Capital level punishment for the most egregious crimes, such as using psychic
powers to commit heinous acts.

</Document>
