<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Chief-Engineer <119664036+Chief-Engineer@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  # Core Rule 4 - Lone antagonists are unbound by (most) rules

  With the exception of metagaming/comms, bug/exploit abuse, erotic/creepy stuff, OOC in IC or IC in OOC, or spawn-camping arrivals, solo antagonists may pursue any goals they wish, in any way they wish.And no, this does not mean you get to mass sabotage John Shitter. Look at (link to gameplay rules) for a better understanding but escalation and roleplay is key.

  To put it in simple terms, if you put the effort into your roleplay, then you can escalate to your hearts content.

  Crewmembers are not allowed to pre-emptively search for, hinder, or otherwise seek conflict with antagonists without reasonable cause to do so. Otherwise, they may handle antagonists in any way they wish, provided they understand that their actions may be punished by Space Law if given IC cause. Team antagonists can do as they wish as per lone antagonists, but their actions should neither harm their teams efforts, nor intentionally harm it through inaction. Emulating an antagonist by action or outfit puts you at risk of being treated as one.

  ## Precedents

  - Regular crewmembers can assist antagonists with good IC reasoning, but assisting an antagonist doesn't mean you get a pass on acting like one. If in doubt, ask an admin if a particular action is okay. Depending on the level of assistance, sufficient IC reasoning ranges from treating everyone who goes into medbay regardless of their history, to bartering contraband, to performing actions under threat of death.
  - Ghosting out mid-conversion/deconversion, going AFK, suiciding, or logging off after conversion/deconversion can result administrative action if done in bad faith. Let an admin know if you cannot or do not want to play any of the above mentioned roles so they may be offered to a willing participant.

  ## Antagonist Directive Priorities
  - In situations where you wind up with multiple simultaneous antagonist assignments (i.e. a Revolutionary and a Traitor), your team goals, objectives, and directives should take precedence. Furthermore, if someone had to go out of their way to convert you to their team, their goals, objectives, and directives become the priority. Refer to the following flowchart:
  - Blob/Zombie -> Brainwash/Construct orders/Silicon Laws -> Cult/Heretic -> Revs -> Wizard Apprentice/Abductor Teams/Niche antags -> Nuke Ops -> Traitors

</Document>
