<Document>
    All Information included in this document is licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0, and is taken from https://wiki.aurorastation.org/index.php?title=Sol_Alliance with some modifications.

    # Solarian Alliance

    - [bold]Home System:[/bold] [italic] Sol[/italic]
    - [bold]Homeworld:[/bold] Earth
    - [bold]Capital:[/bold] Unity Station, Earth's Orbit
    - [bold]Language(s):[/bold] Sol Common
    - [bold]Founded:[/bold] June 15th, 2132
    - [bold]Political Entities:[/bold] Alliance of Sovereign Solarian Nations
    - [bold]Military Force:[/bold] Solarian Armed Forces including its Navy, Marine Corps, Army, and Planetary Defense Forces. Given the prevalence of its Navy, the Solarian armies are commonly abbreviated as SAN.
    - [bold]Special Notes:[/bold] [color=#ff0000]Non-Humans cannot be citizens of the Sol Alliance. No alien has ever served in the Solarian Armed Forces.[/color]
    - [bold]Synthetic Rights:[/bold] [color=#ff0000]None. Synthetics; including IPCs, Cyborgs, and Artificial Intelligences, are legally considered state property.[/color]

    ## Overview
    Though its power has waned following the disastrous events of late 2462, this federal union remains the home of humanity and the one of the premier powers in the Orion Spur.
    Formerly held back by bureaucratic corruption, administrative inefficiency, an overstretched legal system, systemic political infighting, and economic troubles that led to over a century of decline and waning influence culminating in its retreat inwards, many now look to reform the Alliance into a more effective political force.

    The Alliance of Sovereign Solarian Nations (ASSN), commonly referred to as the Solarian Alliance, the Sol Alliance, and sometimes the Alliance, is a federal union of 70 member state star systems, and 198 dependencies including the Eridani Corporate Federation.
    Dependencies vary between undeveloped star systems and outposts on asteroids, to sprawling space stations and include the capital of the Sol Alliance: the bustling Unity Station in orbit over Earth. The Sol Alliance is divided into two administrative sections known as the Inner and Middle Rings.

    Day by day, the power and influence of the Sol Alliance diminishes. At the present, she is beset upon by the most insidious and unstoppable forces known to to all empires, that of simple economics. Her coffers have been bled dry for decades, her budgets padded by seemingly endless credit.
    Yet from an outside perspective, the Alliance is seemingly at its xenith, as though they are the mightiest and largest they have ever been. The cracks in this empire can be seen in the dirt accumulating in the corners of pristine ship bridges, buildings going without paint, marines going without pay.

    Desertion from her armies has grown to an all-time high year after year, ever increasing. These issues drive the Sol Alliance towards seemingly endless compliance actions against worlds at her periphery, and in particular against that of the recently formed Biesel Republic.
    Oftentimes the Alliance gives shaky justifications for "Compliance", stating that they are merely acting on behalf of oppressed parties and individuals in need of help. In reality, the Sol Navy is pointed like a sword at every world in the periphery by transtellar corporations, corrupt politicians, and individuals of particular influence, all of them like vultures scavenging whatever they find in the ruins.
    Money changes hands, the Navy moves to plant boots on necks, and Corporations grow fat with wealth taken from the "Neo-Barbs" at the edges of the empire.

    ## Demographics
    - [textlink="Solarian-Standard Humans" link="Human"]: Officially, 100%. There are somewhere between 40 and 65 billion humans residing in the Sol Alliance.
    The Solarian Census only records individuals who are citizens, and there are no non-human citizens by policy.
    Unofficially, there exists an underclass of non-humans who make up a significant portion of the population.
    - [bold]All Other Species[/bold]: Anywhere from 25% to 38% of the Sol Alliance population is composed of non-human residents. Their specific numbers and demographics are not recorded, and neutral census takers are often imprisoned when caught trying to count the non-humans.

</Document>
