<Document>
    # Tau-Ceti Foreign Legion
    Also known as: TCFL, Biesel Foreign Legion.

    - [bold]Allegiance:[/bold] [italic]Biesel Republic, Tau-Ceti Armed Forces[/italic]
    - [bold]Allies:[/bold] [italic]NanoTrasen(Primary source of funding)[/italic]
    - [bold]Recruitment:[/bold] [italic]100% Volunteer, open to any nationality or species. No questions asked.[/italic]
    - [bold]Demographics:[/bold] [italic]Between 70-80% former Solarians, the remainder are a mixture of all known alien species.[/italic]
    - [bold]Special Notes[/bold] [italic]The Biesel Republic grants automatic citizenship to all who volunteer for 2 years of service in the TCFL[/italic]

    ## Overview
    One of the most recognized symbols of the Republic of Biesel, the Tau Ceti Foreign Legion (TCFL) was the first official attempt at creating a standing army for the Republic's defence.
    Today, it operates in much the same way - in exchange for at least two years of service, less fortunate immigrants to the Republic may be granted citizenship and meagre pay so that they can establish new, profitable lives within it.
    Although they are frequently underfunded and underequipped in comparison to other parts of Biesel's Armed Forces, the TCFL is by far one of the Republics most decorated military organizations. The TCFL is currently at the forefront of a growing conflict with the Solarian Alliance,
    which has been made more fierce by the open inclusion of former Solarians within its ranks.

    Members of the Foreign Legion are seen by the public as a beacon of Liberty, Democracy, and freedom from the tyranny of the Sol Alliance. Yet despite overwhelmingly high praise from the public, the actual life of a foreign legionnaire is harsh. And with the growing intensity of conflict with Sol,
    a Legionnaire is almost guaranteed direct combat with an enemy that is certain to be just as well armed as they are. Their equipment is an eclectic mixture of abandoned Solarian wargear, Corporate sponsored kits, and cheap weapons from locally sourced Biesel manufacturers.

    ## Legal
    All Information included in this document is licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0, and is taken from https://wiki.aurorastation.org/index.php?title=Tau_Ceti_Armed_Forces with some modifications.
</Document>
