<Document>
  The following outlines the categories of restricted gear aboard NanoTrasen property. Unauthorized possession or use of these items is considered a violation of corporate regulations and may be met with disciplinary action. Access and permissions are clearly defined based on job roles.

  # Space Law: Restricted Gear

  - [color=#cb0000]\[ERT/Central Command\][/color] Equipment and clothing exclusive to Emergency Response Teams (ERT) or Central Command personnel
  - [color=#cb0000]\[Command\][/color] Command-level clothing and equipment, including headsets with encrypted channels or access overlays
  - [color=#cb0000]\[Security\][/color] Security clothing, protective gear, and equipment
  - [color=#cb0000]\[Security\][/color] Less-than-lethal and non-lethal weaponry, excluding general-purpose disablers and beanbag shotguns
  - [color=#cb0000]\[Security\][/color] Flash technology (e.g., flashbang grenades, flash projectors), excluding handheld flashes
  - [color=#cb0000]\[Security\][/color] Helmets, riot shields, and ballistic shields
  - [color=#cb0000]\[Security\][/color] Security HUDs and restraining gear (e.g., handcuffs)
  - [color=#cb0000]\[Security/Command\][/color] Disablers and restraining gear used by authorized personnel
  - [color=#cb0000]\[Security/Command\][/color] Security HUDs
  - [color=#cb0000]\[Security/Command/Bartender\][/color] Protective vests and chest rigs designed to mitigate damage from projectiles or blunt force
  - [color=#cb0000]\[Security/Bartender\][/color] Beanbag shotguns (Bartenders may only use them within station bar premises)
  - [color=#cb0000]\[Security/Science/Command\][/color] Handheld flashes
  - [color=#cb0000]\[Engineering\][/color] Engineering goggles, and Rapid Construction Devices
  - [color=#cb0000]\[None\][/color] Unauthorized PDA software
  - [color=#cb0000]\[None\][/color] Ammunition or explosives not issued by NanoTrasen
  - [color=#cb0000]\[None\][/color] Body armor or tactical suits unauthorized for use by crew roles
  - [color=#cb0000]\[None\][/color] Communication equipment designed to intercept, decrypt, or bypass corporate channels
  - [color=#cb0000]\[None\][/color] Terrorist paraphernalia, including items with clear indicators of association with hostile organizations
</Document>
