<Document>

Take the time to read and understand the rules. Game Administrators will treat you as if you have read the rules and understand them when enforcing the rules, even if you have not and do not. Any violations of the rules will have immediate consequences, up to and including a voucher ban. You should not hesitate to ask a Game Administrator for clarification on the rules in an ‘AHelp’, or Administrator Help, using the Function 1 key on your keyboard or by clicking the ‘Open admin help’ button located on your in-game screen’s UI. 

All other relevant information on how to play the game or learn its mechanics can be read and understood by opening the ‘Guidebook’. You can open the ‘Guidebook’ by pressing the 0 key on your numeric pad located on your keyboard or by clicking the ‘Open guidebook menu’ button located on your in-game screen’s UI. Alternatively, you can use ‘AHelp’ if the guidebook is insufficient to answer any questions you may have.

Consider joining our Discord server for further clarification, help, and community. You can join our Discord between rounds during the pre-game lobby, where a button located on your in-game screen’s UI will appear. Alternatively, you can type in the following URL in to your browser’s search bar: https://discord.gg/eNVZYeppEf



0. Game Administrator Authority:

The Game Administrators (GAs) have the authority to interpret, enforce, and suspend the rules if and when it is necessary to uphold the integrity of the game, server, and community. All rulings made by GAs during active rounds are final and binding, even if you disagree with their actions and/or interpretation of a rule.

Deliberately exploiting ambiguities or technicalities in the rules ("rule lawyering") to gain an advantage or achieve personal goals is strictly prohibited. If you are unsure whether an action violates the rules, refrain from doing it until you clarify with a GA via ‘AHelp’.

If a GA determines that you have an overall negative impact on the community, you may be banned. This determination is based on your behavior, rule violations, and overall contribution to the community.

You can use ‘AHelp’ or submit a ticket on the Frostbite Discord server if you disagree with a GA’s ruling or behavior. All GAs are responsible for their behaviour and any rulings they make, and complaints will be reviewed by senior staff.


1. Players must be and act at least 18+ years old:
This community is strictly for adults (18+). You will be banned for demonstrated immaturity, and/or proof of being underage.

2. You Must Roleplay:
The goal of our server is to immerse players in a fictional universe, enabling them to roleplay with each other. Your character is a grown adult working on a research station for a major company. You are a professional; act like it. Have a sensible name, construct a character for yourself and behave as the character would, and avoid breaking the immersion. 

3. You Must Do Your Job:
Antagonists are exempt from this rule at all times. You are generally expected to know the basics of your job by reading the guidebook. Some leeway is granted to new players, but you should seek out instruction in character from your peers. You should also do your job and not ignore your responsibilities. Assistants are expected to assist, and Gimmick roles are expected to facilitate roleplay via their gimmick.

4. Central Command Standards:
These roles are not for new players and are whitelist only. Central Command actively mindshields and monitors its employees through trackers/recorders and controls them through kill switches, so if you choose to play as part of CC (ERT, NTR, BSO) you MUST follow your role's SOP, ROE, and orders to the letter.


5. Command, Security, and Justice Standards:
These roles are not for new players. Inexperienced players should avoid them. As part of these departments you are actively mindshielded but are not monitored like direct employees of CC are. You may act outside the law, disobey orders, and abuse your power, but can face in-character repercussions if your actions are witnessed and reported. However, remember – you are ALWAYS crew-aligned. 

6. Antagonist Standards:
While antagonists are supposed to be the enemies of the station, above all you should seek to make the round more engaging and fun as the star of the show. Succeeding as an antagonist is not the "goal" of SS14, the goal is for all players to have fun. While there are no friendly antagonists, don't seek to intentionally ruin the round for others just because you're an antagonist.

7. Do Not Grief:
Defined as the perceived intent of one player wanting to cause grief or annoyance to other players or to the server without any roleplay/IC reason. The emphasis is on "intent". If a GA believes that the player's intent is to grief then action will be taken. Any damage to the station or players caused by griefing can be repaired at an Admin's discretion.

8. Be Respectful:
Do not try to intentionally ruin other people's fun. While dying is a normal part of the game and IC conflicts will arise, be patient with other players who may not know what they're doing and assist them when you can; remember this is a newbie-friendly server before anything else and toxicity toward players for not understanding something will not be tolerated. In the spirit of this rule, no racial/homophobic slurs or generally intolerant behavior is permitted in or outside of the game. In-character speciesism between different species is permitted, but keep real-world slurs (including allusions to real slurs) and references out of it

9. Zero Tolerance for Discrimination:
In-character speciesism between different species is permitted, albeit against Space Law, but any and all forms of real world hate speech, marginalization, and discrimination either in-character (IC) or out-of-character (OOC) is strictly prohibited. This includes the use of, alluding to, or making allegories towards real word slurs and epithets. GAs can not reliably know if you are part of a minority who has reclaimed a slur or epithet, therefore, you will not be exempt even if you are.


10. Zero Tolerance for Macros, Exploits, or Cheating:
Macros are defined as Predefined scripts or tools that automate gameplay actions. Simple macros for non-competitive tasks (e.g., emote shortcuts, "Help!" hotkeys) are exempt from this rule.

Exploits are defined as the player abusing bugs, glitches, or unintended mechanics for an advantage. If it feels unintended, report it using the ‘AHelp’ system instead of exploiting it.

Cheating is defined as the deliberate use of external tools, hacked clients, or manipulated code to gain an advantage. Aimbots, wallhacks, or speed modifiers are all considered cheating. Unauthorized access of GA tools, crashing the server, DDoS attacks and actions preventing others from playing is also cheating.

11. Metagaming and Meta-communications:
Players are not allowed to use information gained in any way other than from their living character's point of view during an ongoing round, except for information pertaining to their specific job found on the wiki. You may not use information gained through voice communications with other players, while dead as a ghost, or any information stated in any OOC chat. This is considered cheating and violations may result in a lengthy or permanent ban from the server or OOC. Note: If you wish to use meta-comms to help assist/teach new players, contact an admin first and we will likely allow it.

12. Leaving the Game:
If you wish to leave the game, please use the cryopods located in/near the dorms when possible. This will free up your character's job to be filled by a new player.

</Document>
