<Document>
﻿﻿[color=#ff0000]DISCONNECTING FROM OR IGNORING/EVADING COMMUNICATION FROM ADMINS WILL RESULT IN AN APPEAL ONLY BAN. The job gets really hard when you refuse to talk to the Admins, just come to our Discord and talk it out, hurt feelings will not be held.[/color]

[color=#bb00bb]This is the only source of server rules that apply here, which ideally has all the information any regular player should need. Please do not ever hesitate to ask either an Admin in[/color] [color=#DC143C]AHelp (F1)[/color][color=#bb00bb] or in the Discord server if you ever want clarification on the rules.[/color]

We do not have a wiki, instead, we have or will have all the needed information available via Guidebooks (NumPad0), such as how to power the station. If we do not have some bit of information (how to do a job or how specifically to execute something a document says) you may ask an admin via [color=#DC143C]AHelp (F1)[/color] or ask other players via the [color=#66bbff]OOC[/color] or [color=#66e0e0]LOOC[/color] chat channels.

[color=#a4885c]0.[/color] [color=#a4885c]The[/color] [color=#ffd700]Golden[/color] [color=#a4885c]Rule.[/color] Admins may exercise discretion with rules as they see fit. If you rule lawyer or line skirt, you will get removed. Admins will answer for use of this privilege.

[color=#a4885c]1.[/color] Users [color=#ff0000]must[/color] be at least 13 years old to take any part in anything related to this server.

[color=#a4885c]2.[/color] This is an English server, and you are expected to use English when communicating through any server-related channels.

[color=#a4885c]3.[/color] Do not ignore the [color=#DC143C]AHelp[/color] or abuse it by flooding it with garbage, checking for admins before stating a problem (i.e. "hello?", "any admins?" - also called "asking to ask"), or sending messages of no substance.

[color=#a4885c]4.[/color] Attempting to evade game bans will result in an automatic appeal-only permanent ban. Similarly, attempting to evade job bans will result in an appeal-only permanent ban.

[color=#a4885c]5.[/color] Absolutely no hate speech, bigotry, intolerance, or anything remotely similar.

[color=#a4885c]6.[/color] No engaging in sexual acts.

[color=#a4885c]7.[/color] Don't use custom clients, exploits, or external programs to gain an advantage or disrupt the round/server. This includes auto clickers and auto-hotkey scripts.

[color=#a4885c]8.[/color] Don't communicate in-game/in-character information through methods outside the game (such as talking in Discord with other users actively playing about the game or by talking to your sibling across the room while you are both playing). This is referred to as "Metacomming" and it is strictly forbidden.

[color=#a4885c]9.[/color] Don't "multi-key" (use multiple accounts simultaneously). Users knowingly using multiple SS14 accounts will have all of their accounts banned.

[color=#a4885c]10.[/color] Don't use information gained from outside your character's knowledge to gain an advantage (this is referred to as "Metagaming").

[color=#a4885c]11.[/color] Don't rush for or prepare equipment unrelated to your job for no purpose other than to have it "just in case" (referred to as "Powergaming").

[color=#a4885c]12.[/color] Don't immediately ghost, suicide, or cryostasis if you do not get an antagonist role (referred to as "Antag-rolling").
    - This is not fair to other players actually waiting patiently for an antagonist round or wanting good staff. Alternatively, if you do not want to play an antagonist or do not want to cause conflict, do not opt in for antagonist roles.

[color=#a4885c]13.[/color] Act like an actual human being on a space station. Avoid use of text speak or emoticons [color=#bbbbbb]IC[/color], and do not refer to [color=#66bbff]OOC[/color] things like admins in-game. Remember that this is a roleplaying game, and people are expected to try to react to situations realistically, even if it's not the "optimal" thing to do. What's good for Roleplay > What's good for Gameplay.

[color=#a4885c]14.[/color] Don't harass or target players across rounds for actions in prior rounds or for actions outside the game without their approval (this is referred to as "Metagrudging").

[color=#a4885c]15.[/color] Intentionally making yourself a major problem/annoyance/disruption for the crew or other players at large while not an antagonist is forbidden without admin approval (referred to as "self-antagging").

[color=#a4885c]16.[/color] Follow escalation rules and don't murder someone for slipping you, use common sense.
    - Don't outright leave people to die if you get in a fight, make an effort to heal them or bring them to [color=#52B4E9]Medical[/color].
    - [color=#DC143C]AHelp (F1)[/color] the situation if you think someone is over-escalating.

[color=#ff0000]COMMAND/SECURITY RULES[/color]

[color=#a4885c]17.[/color] If you sign up for a [color=#334E6D]Command[/color] or [color=#DE3A3A]Security[/color] role, you are expected to know the basics of the game, your job, and the job(s) you supervise, if any.
    - Don't engage in common troublemaker behavior and lawbreaking as a [color=#334E6D]Command[/color] or [color=#DE3A3A]Security[/color] role.
    - Do not immediately abandon your position as a [color=#334E6D]Command[/color] role and go do whatever you want instead of managing your department/the station.
        - As a [color=#334E6D]Command[/color] role, do not take over the jobs of others. The [color=#334E6D]HoP[/color] is not the [color=#DE3A3A]HoS[/color], for instance, and holds no direct power over Security.

[color=#a4885c]18.[/color] [color=#DE3A3A]Security[/color] should try to remain non-lethal and effect arrests, unless there is a great risk of loss of life.

[color=#a4885c]19.[/color] [color=#DE3A3A]Security[/color] are expected to answer for use of lethal force. [color=#DE3A3A]Security[/color] will be expected to effect arrests of criminals and prevent them from dying while in custody, even if lethal force is used. [color=#DE3A3A]Security[/color] is strongly encouraged, but not required, to clone antagonists and effect a permabrigging or other sentence as deemed appropriate.

[color=#a4885c]20.[/color] [color=#DE3A3A]Security[/color] are expected to protect detainees in their custody to the best of their ability, so as long as it does not come to an unreasonable risk to themselves, the crew, or the station at large to do so.
    - Detainees that die in custody must be revived, unless they have been legally executed.

[color=#a4885c]21.[/color] All [color=#334E6D]Command[/color] jobs should [color=#DC143C]AHelp (F1)[/color] when they need to stop playing. Do not play these roles if you do not expect to be able to finish the round.
    - These roles must exhibit some competency. Incompetence can result in a job ban. [color=#334E6D]Command[/color] roles are designed to lead and manage departments first. They are not intended to become do-it-all members of their departments.
    - Crew promoted to acting heads of staff must step down when an official head of staff arrives at the station. This is to prevent confusion with the Chain of command when the new crew mate arrives.
</Document>
