<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Chief-Engineer <119664036+Chief-Engineer@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 5 - Non-security may only actively hunt global or round-ending threats.
  You should not act like a vigilante if a security force is present unless you have a good in-character roleplay reason to believe a global or round-ending threat exists. Restricted antags that are not automatically global or round ending threats may still become so through their actions in the shift, the stronger your reasoning the more action you can take against them.

  You can always defend yourself and others from violent antagonists.

  Players that choose to act as security will be held to the same standards as security.

  ## Precedents

  - Actively hunting a threat involves seeking out or pursuing that threat outside the bounds of your normal reasonable play area. Players are not expected to ignore antagonists during the normal course of play and may engage with antagonists who are active within their sphere. (Examples: A medical doctor knowing the identity of an active traitor could attack that traitor if that traitor came armed into medbay, likewise an engineer could attack a traitor they spotted breaking into the engine room). Players choosing this route should not attempt to chase down or finish antagonists who retreat from these engagements (unless they have reason to believe that the antagonist constitutes a global or round-ending threat or have a personal reason to do so under other precedents)
  - The dead dog litmus test: Players may hunt specific threats or antagonists who have identifiably done something to wrong that particular player, the Ur-example being that players may seek revenge against those who harm their departmental pets. Players who choose this path are empowered to act as security in regard to that specific threat, but as per the main rule must also follow related restrictions on security play. This can also be applied to an assault of a character you've had significant interactions with, in the current round, and it does not apply to cross-round or OOC friendships.
  - Security are freely empowered to deputise players as they will or to declare states of emergency if they believe themselves unable to handle ongoing issues within the round. These calls should be backed up by the chain of command where possible, and non-security players are free to enquire with security to see if they require assistance if concerned. As per the main rule, deputized players are acting as security and held to security’s standards. (Players consistently asking to be deputized or doing so with little in-character reasoning may be asked to knock it off and just play security)

</Document>
