<Document>
  # Harpy (Homo-Aves sapiens)
  All Information included in this document is licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0, and is written by VMSolidus(Github), also known as raistlin_jag(Discord)

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobHarpyDummy" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Harpies were created during the first 100 years of the colonial period of human civilization, back when the corporations still answered to the Sol Government.
  Their creators were a company called GenetiCorp, now long defunct.
  During it's heyday, GenetiCorp developed processes for converting colonists into forms suitable for the lesser colonized planets with some extreme conditions.
  For the Harpy subtype, these adaptations were created to colonize the moon of a Hycean world, Valyrian 4b(4a referring to the Hycean world itself).
  It is a planet with an incredibly dense atmosphere, measuring just slightly over 150kpa at sea level, with a high oxygen concentration.
  Its host star is extraordinarily rich in the UV spectrum of light, but gives off incredibly dim amounts of red light.
  The planet's terrain features a vast ocean surrounding a single volcanically active continent, as well as extensive archipelagos.
  Valyrian 4b is well known for its flora sporting leaves that fluoresce orange in the nearby star's UV intense light.

  Due to persistent financial troubles, GenetiCorp was bought out by its largest competitor Interdyne long before its first colony ship arrived at the intended destination.
  Shortly after arrival, the original Harpy colonists were repossesed by Interdyne- who had gotten to the planet first in faster ships made after the fact.
  Some Harpy colonists remained on "the Homeworld", while others were kept by the company and gradually spread across the realms of human space.
  Due to the costs of their radical genemodding, most Harpies today are indebted to corporations, owing vast sums of money inherited from their parents.
  These debts are often traded between corporations like stocks, resulting in a wide Diaspora of Harpies around the galaxy, and in turn gives them their extremely diverse coloration.

  ## Biology

  Harpies are biologically classed as a different species than Homo-Sapiens, due to the extreme nature of their original designer genetic modifications rendering them incapable of breeding true with Sol-Standard Humans.
  They are however not true mutants, owing to the stability of their modifications such that they breed naturally as a species.
  However, a "GenetiCorp-Standard Harpy" is readily recognisable as being related to humans thanks in part to retaining many body parts and organs present in the standard human.
  A typical Harpy possesses a human brain, heart, stomach, kidneys, and reproductive organs, with skin not unlike a human- though it may be partially feathered, and can have a rough texture to the touch.

  Their most extreme internal modifications are the possession of a second trachea, leading to a quartet of Avian lung organs.
  A Harpy's breathing is several times more efficient than a Human's at taking in oxygen, and like a bird, they have no separation of "Inhale and Exhale".
  Air enters a Harpy's lungs in a continuous loop via a circular motion through their four lung chambers. Listening to a Harpy breathing via a stethoscope is something like listening to the rhythm of a heartbeat, it is fast and continuous.

  This continuous-flow breathing also permits the use of a highly advanced vocal organ called a Syrinx, which is what enables Harpies to perform iconic ability to imitate nearly any sound.
  This of course comes with a significant trade-off, one that makes for a difficult life for Harpies to live in space.
  They require double the volume of air a human requires, burning through tanks of oxygen twice as fast as any other species.
  They are also substantially vulnerable to air impurities of any kind, and will be readily injured by simple things such as cigarette smoke, or someone hyperventilating in their face.

  ## Unique Languages
- [color=#008ecc]Valyrian Standard[/color]:
  A language descended from eastern european languages of old earth - Valyrian Standard is the commonly spoken tongue of Harpies brought up on their homeworld of Valyrian 4b.
  It is rarely spoken outside of the worlds of its native speakers, and has in modern times been supplanted by the 'Conlangs of the Sol Alliance.
  Its speakers are those who wish to uphold the traditions and beliefs of ancient peoples from before the colonial era.

  ## Other Notes

  - No, Harpies don't lay eggs.
  - In a combination of low-gravity and high atmospheric density, a Harpy is capable of flight. They are however flightless in Terran-Standard Atmospheric conditions.
  - Adult Harpies can be anywhere from 135cm to 190cm tall, with an average height of around 155cm(Human average being roughly 175cm, depending on ethnicity).
  - An average adult male Harpy weighs only 24kg, while an average adult female weighs 18kg. For reference, the average weight of an adult male human is 71kg.
  - Curiously, Harpies do not follow the pattern of sexual dimorphism present in Terran birds. Female Harpies are usually just as colorful(or lack thereof) as their male counterparts.
  - Spacer Harpies(Those not born on the Homeworld), are typically far more colorfully diverse than those native to the Homeworld.

  # Species Traits

  ## Positive Traits
  - [color=#1e90ff]Mimicry[/color]:
  Harpies can mimic almost any sound in the game using emotes, barring only a few exceptions. This includes the voice emotes of every other species.
  The Harpy sound library contains nearly 700 possible sounds. This trait is unique only to Harpies.

  - [color=#1e90ff]Runner[/color]:
  Thanks to their incredibly light build, a Harpy's base running speed is 10% faster than that of a standard Human.

  - [color=#1e90ff]Singer(Advanced)[/color]:
  Harpies have a significantly more advanced variant of the [color=#1e90ff]Singer[/color] trait. This trait gives a Harpy access to an innate Midi Player, as well as a menu for swapping instruments.
  Right click on yourself to open the Swappable Instrument menu, and select from a list of available instruments to mimic. Any of the following conditions both stop and prevent a Harpy from singing:

      * Being Mute

      * Being Zombified

      * Being Dead or Crit

      * Taking more than 5 damage in a single instance

      * Being shoved to the ground


  - [color=#1e90ff]Zero Gravity Flight[/color]:
  Harpies have significantly enhanced acceleration in zero gravity. This trait is shared with Nians.

  - [color=#1e90ff](Limited) True Flight[/color]:
  Harpies have an activatable ability to attempt to fly. In order to fly, a Harpy must have both of their wings unencumbered, either by carrying something in hand, or by being restrained.
  When activated, Flight significantly increases the maximum speed and acceleration of a Harpy, while allowing them to fly over obstacles.
  Using flight costs a significant amount of stamina.

  - [color=#1e90ff]Talons[/color]:
  Functions as per the [color=#1e90ff]Talons[/color] trait. A Harpy's unarmed attacks deal 5 points of Piercing damage.

  ## Negative Traits
  - [color=#ffa500]Asthmatic[/color]:
  Using their powerful Avian Lungs, a Harpy breathes twice as deeply, and twice as often as a standard Human. This results in two key conditions. The first is that all oxygen tanks last half as long for a Harpy.
  The second condition, is that Harpies are uniquely vulnerable to poisonous fumes. When exposed to even a small amount of Carbon Dioxide and or Ammonia, a Harpy will shortly thereafter being to choke.
  Choking can be ended either by moving away from the sources of poisonous fumes(such as rotting bodies, open gas tanks, or several people in an enclosed space with no scrubbers).
  A choking Harpy can also stop themselves from choking by breathing from a tank of Pure Oxygen for at least 6 seconds.

  - [color=#ffa500]Extreme Low Density[/color]:
  The average weight of a Harpy is only 24kg, and can be as low as 10kg, with a maximum of 31kg. Because of this, Harpies suffer from any form of Mass Contests.
  This results in weaknesses such as- but are not limited to:
    - Experiencing more recoil with firearms
    - Being easier to shove down
    - Being easy to pick up by other people
    - Being easy to throw
    - Having a harder time pushing or dragging heavy objects
    - Having weaker melee damage with certain weapons
    - Being thrown extremely easily by Space Wind

  - [color=#ffa500]Hollow Bones[/color]:
  Harpies take 15% greater damage from any source of Brute damage.

  - [color=#ffa500]Ultraviolet Vision[/color]:
  Harpies have a unique kind of eye lens that lets them see in Ultraviolet-Blue-Green, but that they cannot see the color Red. This functions as per the Ultraviolet Vision trait.
  "Ultravision" can also be "Bought off" in character creation by taking the [color=#1e90ff]Trichromat Modification[/color] trait.

  # Unique Traitor Items

  - [color=#1e90ff]Bionic Syrinx[/color]:
  Traitor Harpies can optionally purchase a Bionic Syrinx. This takes the form of an Implant which- when implanted in a Harpy, acts as an internal Voice Changer.
  The Bionic Syrinx will only work on Harpies.

</Document>
