<Document>
 # Oni, The Spur's Giants
(lore written under this section is provided by trashalice on Discord/GitHub)

 <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobOni" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

## Upsides
-35% Blunt melee damage increase, 25% increase for other brute types (can be changed with traits)
-15 extra stamina and increased stamina regeneration
-Higher base mass
-Unique traitor item: the kanabou

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Kanabou" Caption=""/>

## Negatives
-Lower psionic potential, cannot take psi potential traits
-Accuracy with ranged weapons is laughable


## A Brief Introduction
The Oni species seen across a selection of sectors across the galaxy are a hardy, strong (equally in will and body) and of course, large, humanoid species, though are not the fruit of genetic experimentation, rather, a somewhat recently discovered alien species on their homeworld of Linarve-C, a densely forested, warm and humid planet with sections of steppes and mountain ranges. 

The planet houses a rather aggressive host of local fauna alongside the various, diverse Oni clans, ranging from Nomads in the eastern steppes to the mountain dwelling, industrious northern clans, that typically forged many of the traditional Oni weapons and armours that are often seen in various museums and within the buildings of any organisation with a significant amount of Oni within their ranks. 

Linarve-C has weather that is often extreme and hostile to many less rugged lifeforms, with the only usual constant being jungle-like humidity across a significant portion of the planet, monsoons and extreme heat being exceptionally common, and due to a negligible axial tilt of the planet, the conditions hardly ever became less hostile as the planet hardly experienced seasonal change.

## Colonial Effort, the Homeworld of the Oni
Colonisation of the planet was headed by an exploratory fleet of the Zavodskoi Interstellar in hopes of testing its experimental weaponry on the larger predators of the planet, with its genetic research division also finding an interest in the planet's varied ecosystem. The effort of colonisation was troublesome, many colonists struggled to adapt to the dangerous, territorial fauna’s constant assaults on outposts and expeditions and the heavy duty military hardware did not fare well in a humid environment with muddy terrain, in order to reduce damages to corporate assets, the corporation made an effort to begin bargaining with the Oni to aid in the taming of the planet. 
The species as a whole was somewhat split on collaborating with the corporation that had invaded their land, but the promise of advances in technology, safety from less “benevolent” forces and of course, the opportunity to explore the stars, something once thought impossible to many, had began to sway some to aid the invaders in their pursuit to reshape the planet.

Over a decade and a half, a costly campaign was waged by joint Zavodskoi Interstellar forces and teams of Oni, acting as navigators, scouts and translators. The campaign would involve forming more permanent infrastructure, warding fauna from habitation zones and capturing specimens for study from Zavodskoi’s genetics division.
The campaign, was regarded by many as a failure, the planet would not give in to the force of the Corporations, infrastructure for the corporations desires could not be feasibly be met, and defoliating would not be an option, as it would ruin the previous intention of the colonial effort, but some benefits did come of it, the study done on the native life provided exceptionally useful, Oni made for exceptional test subjects with augmentation, as their heavy frames supported augments that would otherwise crush another morphotype. This also allowed for some more sly Clan Elders to get their hands in the corporate world, leveraging the corporation’s failures for reparations, favours and informants, this would lead to the largest clans becoming either part of, or full blown corporations. 

Due to some clans implementation into the corporate world however, the larger Oni clans are regarded with suspicion, much like some of the megacorporations, many believe they sold out their ideals for power, physically and metaphorically strong-arming their competition with blackmail, threats and even violence, Oni assaults can prove debilitating, or fatal. Oni in the modern day often find themselves in Private Security detail and Salvage Operations as their physical prowess, intimidating figure and overall strong wills allow them to flourish in these environments.

## Physiology and Mentality
Oni are, as mentioned previously, significantly larger on average in comparison to various other morphotypes, alongside denser muscle mass and supportive ligaments that allow the Oni’s colossal size to be biologically feasible, a strong cardiovascular system, leading to highly efficient delivery of oxygen throughout the body, allowing for an Oni to work, or in many cases, fight for a prolonged period. The bones and skin of an oni are immensely sturdy, especially after callusing and or scarring, scarring is common cultural tradition among many Oni clans, especially those of nomadic heritage, as it proved the individuals resilience in the face of peril. This was adapted to better combat the various dangerous fauna of their homeworld, which Oni would often overwhelm in ambushes with their raw might. 
Oni also sport horns, similar to many Terran mammals, their size and shape vairy heavily from different lineages, they are the pride and joy of many, some even decorating them with tassels and other jewellery or even shave them to two stumps, though it is rare, seen as a punishment by many Oni societies, some however, have taken to doing it voluntarily for solidarity with those punished by draconian traditions. 

The skeletal structure of an Oni is exceptionally robust, being significantly sturdier than a sol human counterpart, the skull especially, has a remarkably strong forehead and crown, likely reinforced to allow for the horns to be supported, resulting in Oni concussion and brain damage from outside physical trauma being significantly lower than that of other species. Otherwise an Oni is very close in biology to that of a typical sol human, simply scaled up to accomodate a larger, stronger form.

However, the Oni do have some flaws, their accuracy with many firearms, is to put it bluntly, laughable, due to the large, less flexible hands of many Oni, aiming and firing firearms is often problematic. 
Mentally the Oni are often very resolute and steadfast, but have a tendency for bad temperaments, stubbornness and “boar like tenacity, despite the danger to their own person”, their more iron willed minds have lead them to not as strongly be as affected by noospheric interference, many psionic Oni have a weaker developmental potential for psionic ability, but can still possess the raw power of other species, the noosphere’s whims are after all, fickle. 
Oni have a higher chance of developing waveform misalignment, being approximately 35% more likely to develop or be born with the affliction when compared to other sophonts, for this reason the epistemological theory that those with waveform misalignment are not regarded as sophonts, is often unpopular among Oni societies.

Oni pigmentation varies drastically, while it is hard to tell if it is a result of gene modding nowadays, records from the colonisation of Linarvee-c suggest Oni coloration was very varied even prior, suggesting some was a result of certain lineages adapting camoflage for their territories and more urban socieites pre colonisation, those in the upper classes sought for children with more exotic appearances as a status symbol, thankfully this elitism has begun to die down as the species has been introduced to the multiiculturilsm presented by work in various corporate sectors involving differing species and ideals.

</Document>