<Document>
  # Plasmamen

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobPlasmaman" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  They breathe plasma, and oxygen is highly toxic when inhaled.
  Being exposed to oxygen sets them on fire, forcing them to wear envirosuits, EVA suits or hardsuits.

  They come with a [bold]spaceworthy[/bold] envirosuit helmet that provides a flashlight and welding protection.
  However, they cannot eat nor drink without taking off their envirosuit helmet.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingUniformEnvirosuit" Caption="envirosuit"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadEnvirohelm" Caption="envirosuit helmet"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoubleEmergencyPlasmaTankFilled" Caption="plasma internals tank"/>
  </Box>

  They don't have blood and cannot bleed out.
  They don't experience hunger nor thirst.

  They can consume Milk to gain a positive moodlet and slowly heal Brute, Heat, Shock, and Caustic damage.
  They can also consume Plasma to gain a bigger positive moodlet and heal every damage type faster than Milk, except Cellular.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DrinkCartonMilk" Caption="milk carton"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SheetPlasma1" Caption="plasma"/>
  </Box>

  They take [color=#1e90ff]15% less Slash and 25% less Piercing damage[/color],
  and are [color=#1e90ff]immune to Radiation and Cold damage[/color],
  but take [color=#ffa500]50% more Blunt and 50% more Heat damage[/color].

  Due to their [color=#1e90ff]Cold immunity[/color], they can withstand cold environments such as the Glacier Station without the need of a winter coat.

  ## Medical Treatment
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StasisBed" Caption="stasis bed"/>
  </Box>

  To perform surgery on a Plasmaman, you need to take off their envirosuit first, which can be disastrous in an oxygenated environment.

  To get around this, you can buckle the Plasmaman to a [bold]stasis bed[/bold] before removing their envirosuit to prevent them from self-igniting throughout the surgery.

  Their envirosuit helmet prevents them from eating pills, so it's recommended to use a syringe to administer chemicals.

</Document>
