<Document>
  # Shadowkin

    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobShadowkinDummy" Caption=""/>
    </Box>

  Public information on the origins of Shadowkin is incredibly sparse, in part owing to the secretive nature of these creatures. They are known by the Epistemics Cult to have originated from a dimension that is formally known as "The World At The End Of All Time", but any attempts to glean information about this dimension are universally met with silence or hostile stares. Between only their own kind, Shadowkin have many names for this dreadful place, with the most common simply being "The Dark". They have several evolutionary adaptations for living in such an incredibly hostile world. The World At The End Of All Time can thus be assumed from these adaptations to be extraordinarily cold, utterly without visible light, and bearing a thin atmosphere.

  Shadowkin in their current state are valued employees of Nanotrasen and often drift in and out of employment in other companies or sectors of space.
  They are generally known as reliable and trustable employees, not having anything that's exceptionally negative or positive regarding their work ethic.
  They have been known to be hired by security contracting companies and mercenary freelance organizations for their ability to go into the umbra at will.
  Anti-Shadowkin sentiment is not very common among Nanotrasen employees, but certain Shadowkin that continue to interact with the nöösphere and cause problems around themselves have the tendency to draw the ire of local authorities.

  ## Biology

  Shadowkin biology is rather unknown and obscure as there aren't currently many in the sector.
  We do know a few things, one of them being that both male and females look identical on the outside, no apparently gender at first look.
  Shadowkin are very androgynous externally, fur flat against their bodies with no external differences regardless of sex.
  Typically, they come in the two color extremes with the vast majority being dark colors while a rare few are white or grey.
  Shadowkin that have been seen with fur such as orange and teal have consistently and always said their fur was dyed when asked, leading us to believe the darker tones and white are the only natural fur colors.
  Recent autopsies have also revealed that Shadowkin do not seem to have pupils, their eyes simply being large, glowing orbs.
  It is unsure how they see out of these without a visible pupil but it seems that not even they know.
  Unlike other species, Shadowkin have four ears instead of two.
  Their upper two ears are tasked with transmitting thoughts via Empathy, while the lower two ears are tasked with receiving thoughts that were transmitted via Empathy.
  Shadowkin tails are typically fleshy and movable, covered in fur.
  Shadowkin tails come in many shapes and sizes from large and fluffy to short and coarse, the tails do not seem to aid with balance and it's unclear if they do anything in the Dark.
  Shadowkin tongues are also quite versatile, being the only ones capable of communicating effectively with Marish.
  So far, researchers have struggled and been unable to find a manner to put Marish into a translator in a way that is accurate or understandable.

  ## Unique Language

- [color=#2c2d33]Marish[/color]:
  Marish is the unique and special language of the Shadowkin that was developed when they started moving out of the Dark and into normal dimensions.
  Marish is a language that can only be properly spoken by someone with a Shadowkin tongue, other organic tongues and even computers struggling to get a proper grasp on it.
  Marish is separate from Empathy in the fact that it is spoken while Empathy is typically communicated by vibrating one's four ears.

  ## Misc. Notes

  - Shadowkin, unlike harpies, do in fact hatch from eggs.
  - Shadowkin on average tend to be slightly smaller than the average human, a few getting maybe a couple inches taller but not by much.
  - Shadowkin do not have a concept of gender, rather only that of biological sex; this is primarily due to the fact that both males and females look identical on the outside.
  - Shadowkin primarily used to live as nomadic tribals, as more of them populate different dimensions, this has begun to change.
  - Shadowkin personalities are primarily dictated by their eye color, find out all the personalities!

  ## Species Traits
  ### Positive Traits
  -[color=#303056]Barrel Chested[/color]:
  Shadowkin, as a result of living in a dimension where there is little air, do not have lungs but instead a core. Their core allows them to more efficiently process oxygen and not use as much as a result.

  -[color=#303056]Innate Telepathy[/color]:
  Shadowkin are innately telepathic, allowing them to communicate with other psionic individuals at will.

  -[color=#303056]Psionic Species[/color]:
  Shadowkin as a species inhabit a unique ability to more easily learn new psionic abilities, in part owing to their home dimension being incredibly hostile to those who would be considered "normal".

  -[color=#303056]Resting[/color]:
  Shadowkin are able to fall into a deep and powerful sleep to quickly recover mana to use their psionic abilities sooner than others.

  ### Negative Traits
  -[color=#303056]Glass Cannon[/color]:
  Shadowkin are very vulnerable to damage from an array of sources, preferring speed and agility over direct combat.

  -[color=#303056]Easy Target[/color]:
  Due to the fact they're inherently psionic, they make for easy targets by over-eager epistemics staff... and any other beasts that lurk in the dark.

  -[color=#303056]Unfortunate Evolution[/color]:
  Most Shadowkin are not very tall, rendering them easy to pick up and throw around. As a result, space wind hits them 20% harder and their bones are not very durable either.
</Document>
