<Document>
  # Shadowkin

    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobShadowkinDummy" Caption=""/>
    </Box>

  The origins of Shadowkin are largely disputed among scholars as nobody really knows exactly where they're from,  only that they started appearing one day. 
  What is widely accepted is that they're not from this universe, this dimension, or this plane of existence. 
  We know that they originate from a dimension they simply refer to as "the Dark" with not much explanation other than that. 
  They have several evolutions that have allowed them to continue in the way they are currently. 
  The chief theory is that Shadowkin are beings created by the nöösphere and that the Dark where they live is in fact the nöösphere itself, but this theory remains hotly contested due to the implications.

  Shadowkin in their current state are valued employees of Nanotrasen and often drift in and out of employment in other companies or sectors of space.
  They are generally known as reliable and trustable employees, not having anything that's exceptionally negative or positive regarding their work ethic.
  They have been known to be hired by security contracting companies and mercenary freelance organizations for their ability to go into the umbra at will.
  Anti-Shadowkin sentiment is not very common among Nanotrasen employees, but certain Shadowkin that continue to interact with the nöösphere and cause problems around themselves have the tendency to draw the ire of local authorities. 

  ## Biology

  Shadowkin biology is rather unknown and obscure as there aren't currently many in the sector. 
  We do know a few things, one of them being that both male and females look identical on the outside, no apparently gender at first look.
  Shadowkin are very androgynous externally, fur flat against their bodies with no external differences regardless of sex.
  Typically, they come in the two color extremes with the vast majority being dark colors while a rare few are white or grey.
  Shadowkin that have been seen with fur such as orange and teal have consistently and always said their fur was dyed when asked, leading us to believe the darker tones and white are the only natural fur colors.
  Recent autopsies have also revealed that Shadowkin do not seem to have pupils, their eyes simply being large, glowing orbs.
  It is unsure how they see out of these without a visible pupil but it seems that not even they know. 
  Unlike other species, Shadowkin have four ears instead of two.
  Their upper two ears are tasked with transmitting thoughts via Empathy, while the lower two ears are tasked with receiving thoughts that were transmitted via Empathy.
  Shadowkin tails are typically fleshy and movable, covered in fur.
  Shadowkin tails come in many shapes and sizes from large and fluffy to short and coarse, the tails do not seem to aid with balance and it's unclear if they do anything in the Dark.
  Shadowkin tongues are also quite versatile, being the only ones capable of communicating effectively with Marish. 
  So far, researchers have struggled and been unable to find a manner to put Marish into a translator in a way that is accurate or understandable.

  ## Unique Language

- [color=#2c2d33]Marish[/color]:
  Marish is the unique and special language of the Shadowkin that was developed when they started moving out of the Dark and into normal dimensions.
  Marish is a language that can only be properly spoken by someone with a Shadowkin tongue, other organic tongues and even computers struggling to get a proper grasp on it.
  Marish is separate from Empathy in the fact that it is spoken while Empathy is typically communicated by vibrating one's four ears.
  Marish can be combined with Empathy to be spoken and transmitted at the same time, this is most common in small areas like stations where Shadowkin know each other.
  When Marish is combined with Empathy, it is known as Marish but in this form it's quite frequently exclusively used to communicate across far distances like Empathy rather than close spoken communication like Marish.

  ## Misc. Notes

  - Shadowkin, unlike harpies, do in fact hatch from eggs.
  - Shadowkin on average tend to be slightly smaller than the average human, a few getting maybe a couple inches taller but not by much.
  - Shadowkin do not have a concept of gender, rather only that of biological sex; this is primarily due to the fact that both males and females look identical on the outside.
  - Shadowkin primarily used to live as nomadic tribals, as more of them populate different dimensions, this has begun to change.
  - Shadowkin personalities are primarily dictated by their eye color, find out all the personalities!

  ## Species Traits
  ### Positive Traits
  -[color=#303056]Lack of Lungs[/color]:
  Shadowkin, as a result of living in a dimension where there is no air, do not have lungs. Their lack of lungs means they do not have the need to breathe.

  -[color=#303056]Empathy[/color]:
  Shadowkin have their own language called Marish. In this case, it is a combination of Empathy and Marish that allows them to have a species hivemind.

  -[color=#303056]Latent Psionic[/color]:
  Shadowkin as a species are latent psionics, thus they can hear telepathy at all times. Telepathy is separate from their own hivemind.

  -[color=#303056]Resting[/color]:
  Shadowkin are able to fall into a deep and powerful sleep to quickly recover mana to use their psionic abilities sooner than others.

  ### Negative Traits
  -[color=#303056]Glass Cannon[/color]:
  Shadowkin are very vulnerable to damage from a vast majority of sources, rendering them glass cannons.

  -[color=#303056]Easy Target[/color]:
  Due to the fact they're inherently psionic, they make for easy targets by over-eager epistemics staff.

  -[color=#303056]Unfortunate Evolution[/color]:
  Most Shadowkin are not very tall, rendering them easy to pick up and throw around. As a result, space wind hits them 20% harder and their bones are not very durable either.
</Document>
