<Document>
  # Shell (I.P.C. Variant)

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PositronicBrain" Caption="Brain"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobIPCDummy" Caption="Inside"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobHumanDummy" Caption="Outside"/>
  </Box>

  Shells are a highly specialized variant of IPC that was originally pioneered by the Einstein Engines corporation in the year 2450. A Shell is essentially an IPC that has been constructed to heavily resemble a human being.
  The resemblance however is only skin-deep, as underneath layers of synthetic skin and pseudo-pigment lies a fully functional robotic being with a positronic brain.
  They are typically trained using data-packs which impart a higher degree of social skills than are found in baseline models. As a caveat, they are typically not as well suited to industrial labor as their baseline counterparts.

  It is not unusual to see Shells being made to work in service industries, in fact they are highly suitable for these kinds of jobs. Of course they can also be employed in any kind of job that a baseline IPC could potentially work in.
  Older shells are almost impossible to mistake for a human, often featuring rubbery skin and exposed hydraulics. While modern, top-of-the-line Shells are incredibly difficult to tell apart from humans.

  Most Mega-corporations have their own in-house manufacturing facilities for Shells, and typically produce ones that are specialized relevant to their own target market.

  ## Naming Conventions

  Shell names typically fall into two different categories, Manufacturer Designation, or Self-Named. Shells owned by a corporation will typically have names such as "NT-89234790", "Z.I. Apollo", "Hazel #HS3-8342", and so on, with many variations.
  While Shells that are self-owned have the freedom to elect their own names, most of these will either retain their original owned name, or come up with something unique.

  In some cases, Shells may use actual human names. Some owners actually insist on human names, while self-owned Shells may pick a regular human name just for convenience.

  ## Roleplaying Guidelines

  The first thing to remember is that Shells are not humans. Inside their head is a highly sophisticated digital brain, that may or may not have a soul depending on the people arguing. They usually won't think, act, or want the same ways a human will.
  By contrast, Shells are (usually) extremely good at pretending to be humans. It's what they were designed to do! Imitating human expressions, faking emotions that they don't have, and tricking humans into thinking they have a soul, are all parts of a Shell's intended purpose.
  Although the Shell is most likely faking these, it's largely up to you the player to decide which of its emotions are fake or not.

  The most important thing to a Shell is self-preservation. The better they are at faking humanity, the more suitable they are for their original purpose, and the more likely they will continue to get routine maintenance. Shells are highly sophisticated machines,
  with equally sophisticated maintenance bills. Oftentimes, self-ownership is a trap which draws Shells into an endless debt-cycle of always having to buy expensive replacement parts. Whereas corporate-owned Shells live a grueling existence of 20 hour work days, 7 days a week,
  yet enjoy never needing worry about when the next maintenance check-up will be.

  ## Creating a Shell

  Creating a Shell character is slightly different from creating any other species. To start, one must create and customize a "human" character to serve as its appearance. Then, to distinguish the character as a shell,
  simply select the [color=#008ecc]Species Swap: Shell[/color] trait.

  - [color=#1e90ff]Shells share all of the same mechanical features as IPCs.[/color]

  - [color=#1e90ff]Most traits that are unique to IPCs can also be taken by Shells.[/color]

  - [color=#ffa500]Shells contain zero organic components, and are not living beings.[/color]

</Document>
