<Document>
  # Tajaran
  All Information included in this document is licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0, and is taken from https://wiki.aurorastation.org/index.php?title=Tajaran with some modifications by SX-7(Github).
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobTajaran" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  The Tajara (direct plural: Tajara – Tah-jaw-rah both singular and multiple) (adjective: Tajaran - Tah-jaw-ran) are a race of humanoids that possess markedly felinoid traits that include a semi-prehensile tail, a body covered in fur of varying shades, and padded, digitigrade feet.
  Tajaran history and society is deeply entrenched in the conflict between its caste system and ruling governments.
  The species currently finds itself involved in a cold war between the three powers that control its homeworld, Adhomai.

  # Biology

  To the average human, the Tajara share many similarities with Earth's felines; however, when looked at from a purely scientific perspective, this description is largely superficial.
  Unlike terrestrial felines, the Tajara are both omnivorous and bipedal.
  Their bodies are almost entirely covered in a thick coat of fur that is extremely good at insulating them from the extreme cold of Adhomai.
  The layer of body fat and fur is designed to trap body heat efficiently.
  There are only a handful of areas where fur is not present, those being on the palm of their hands, the soles of their feet, and a number of various orifices as well as a small area around their eyes.
  Tajara have nictitating membranes, a transparent eyelid layer that assists in preventing snow blindness and keeping their eyes moist against the wind.

  Occasionally, the fur around a Tajara's neck is known to grow into a shaggy 'mane' of sorts, giving them a distinct look, not unlike a terran lion.
  This hair tends to be much stronger and a great deal wirier than the rest of the fur on a Tajara's body.
  Some Tajara tend towards monochromatic bodies while others have multicolor or even calico fur patterns.
  These designs depend heavily on the genetics of the individual's parents, much like hair and eye color.
  Because of this, some parents are utterly incapable of producing multicolor children.
  Designs including flat colors, stripes, spots, and most conceivable combinations have been recorded by scientists both Tajaran and human.
  A male Tajara is somewhere between 150 cm and 185 cm in height, while the mean body mass is between 65 kg and 100 kg.
  Females tend to range between 150 cm and 175 cm in height, with their own weight somewhere around 45 kg to 85kg.
  As such, both their body weight and height are roughly comparable to the average human.
  Height depends on a Tajara's ethnicity.
  Njarir'akhran were bred to be taller, M'sai are a more middle height, Hharar are typically shorter or of middle height, and Zhan-Khazan are usually the tallest of the races.
  Any Tajara who falls out of this range is unusually tall or short which typically stems from a medical condition.
  A Tajaran fetus only takes six months to mature, and Tajaran children likewise mature rapidly, reaching the full extent of their growth by 15 or 16.
  This rapid maturation has a profound effect on the lifespan of Tajara, as only with modern medicine have Tajara reached ages above 70, with the oldest living Tajara being 84 years old.
  Most Tajara retire at age 60 when they are too old to work in any capacity.

  ## Ethnicities

  There are four races of Tajara: the Hharar, the Zhan-Khazan, the Njarir’Akhran, and the M'sai.
  Each race has a common role that they play in a society to which their biological inclinations make them more suited, as well as their own cultures which have formed from long histories of performing these roles in society.
  Tajara heavily stereotype each other based on race which is often a cause for conflict.
  As a result of these differences, there is a lot of racial tension between these various types of Tajara which was further exacerbated by differences in socioeconomic classes.

  ### Hharar

  The first Tajaran ethnicity that Humanity came in contact with is generally viewed as the 'typical Tajara', which is reinforced by their numerical superiority over the other groups.
  Additionally, given their large numbers and capabilities, they most often serve in governmental positions and as ambassadors to other races; this leads to them being taken as the 'face' of the Tajaran race, as it were. Hharar trend towards being the most intellectual of all Tajaran groups, and as such their physical prowess is significantly reduced.
  The Hharar are the stereotypical 'worker' Tajara, commonly described as loyal employees who are passionate and not afraid to voice their opinions.

  ### Zhan-Khazan

  The second most populous of Tajaran ethnicities, and are considered to be the backbone of the Tajaran workforce.
  Because of their history of hard work and the way they adapted to harsh mountain life, Zhan-Khazan are more physically intimidating than other Tajara.
  Featuring more toned, muscular bodies, thicker fur coats, and heavier body weight, they are well-suited to tasks requiring brute strength and heavy lifting.
  Due to their status as laborer they suffer discrimination and are usually regarded as less intelligent.

  ### M'sai

  The third most populous Tajaran ethnic group, the M'sai were at one point the hunters for ancient Tajara and evolved to have lithe, slender forms, and light fur that hid them in the blizzards on Adhomai.
  As Tajaran society advanced, M'sai could be found in many roles related to combat, including law enforcement and military service.
  They are very loyal to their friends and family but aren't as overt about it as the Zhan-Khazan.
  With wide eyes and acute senses, they make great soldiers, with a vision adapted to compensate for the heavy blizzards that plague their home planet.
  They are also great survivalists and are capable of scrounging food for themselves via hunting.

  ### Njarir’Akhran

  The ethnic group that made up the majority of the plutocracy before the Great War.
  Their lineage can be traced from careful breeding between Hharar and M'sai, leading to where they currently are today.
  Following recent events on Adhomai, Njarir make up less than ten percent of the population.
  Easily identifiable by their large ears, fluffy tails, luxurious fur, and slender, elegant features.
  Njarir suffer persecution and rejection from certain proponents of Tajaran society because of their bloodline.
  As the most learned of all Tajaran ethnic groups, they boast high intelligence and have a propensity towards the arts and sciences.

  # History

  Adhomai, the Tajaran homeworld, has long been ruled by a deeply entrenched nobility.
  Historical records dating back 3,000 years describe monarchies supported by religious authorities, where rulers claimed divine origins.
  These local monarchies evolved into feudal systems where peasants lived under oppressive conditions, enforced by M’sai enforcers.
  Over centuries, noble families like the Njarir’Akhran solidified their control, hoarding technological and scientific advancements while imposing harsh laws.
  Tensions between nobility and peasants escalated with industrialization in the 18th and 19th centuries.
  The invention of the printing press in 1756 CE spread anti-monarchist sentiments despite strict censorship.
  By the mid-20th century, industrialization exacerbated inequalities, with peasants laboring in mines and on railways for the nobles' benefit.
  Resentment reached a peak, paving the way for revolution.

  Human discovery in 2418 CE introduced new ideas of equality and freedom, fueling Tajaran uprisings.
  The First Revolution began in 2421 CE after a public execution incited armed rebellion.
  By 2431 CE, the rebels, aided by defecting nobles like the Hadii family, overthrew the old order at the cost of over 92 million lives.

  The People's Republic of Adhomai was established under Hadii leadership in 2432 CE, backed by human corporations like NanoTrasen.
  However, disagreements over resource control led to the Second Revolution in 2451 CE, resulting in a decade-long conflict.
  By 2461 CE, a cold war emerged among three factions: the People's Republic, the Democratic People's Republic, and the New Kingdom of Adhomai.

  Today, Adhomai remains divided, marked by ongoing tensions, proxy wars, and an uneven modernization process.
  While urban centers thrive, rural areas struggle, and foreign influence continues to shape the Tajaran future.
  The species navigates a precarious path, torn between progress and the scars of its feudal past.


  # Species Traits

  - [color=#1e90ff]Animal Diet[/color]: Tajara are poisoned by theobromine but can safely consume uncooked animal protein.

  - [color=#1e90ff]Cold Resistance[/color]: Tajara are more resilient to cold than humans, receiving [color=#1e90ff]35% less cold damage[/color] and [color=#1e90ff]tolerating lower temperatures[/color].

  - [color=#1e90ff]Hairballs[/color]: Tajara can spit out hairballs, which cause others to vomit when held.

  - [color=#1e90ff]Claws[/color]: Tajara unarmed attacks deal Slash damage instead of Blunt.

  - [color=#1e90ff]Reflexes[/color]: Tajara take reduced damage from high-speed impacts.

  - [color=#1e90ff]Small Body[/color]: Tajara are small enough to fit in duffelbags.

  - [color=#1e90ff]Night Vision[/color]: Tajara can see in darkness.

  - [color=#1e90ff]Light Step[/color]: Thanks to their furred paw pads, Tajara can walk silently when not wearing shoes.

  - [color=#ffa500]Heat Intolerance[/color]: Tajara take [color=#ffa500]35% more Heat damage[/color] and burn more easily. They also [color=#ffa500]suffer more damage from overheating[/color].

  - [color=#ffa500]Light Build[/color]: Their small stature makes Tajara take 15% more Brute damage, and they are lighter than humans.

  - [color=#ffa500]Weak Body[/color]: Tajara take 15% more stamina damage.

  - [color=#ffa500]Sensitive Eyes[/color]: Tajara are more vulnerable to flashes.

  - [color=#ffa500]Fast Metabolism[/color]: Tajara require more food to sustain themselves.

</Document>


