<Document>
  # Voidborn

    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobVoidbornDummy" Caption=""/>
    </Box>

  Voidborn are a rarity and an anomaly within Sector Crescent, not seeming to belong to any known faction or have a set point of origin.
  Many have described meeting them as simply realizing they had appeared one day. Due to their make-up, they have been labeled as "fog rats" by a vast majority of the sector.
  Those who have encountered them often report a sense of unease, as if the Voidborn are not entirely present, physically or mentally.
  Due to their lack of understanding emotion, Voidborn often resort to copying and imitating the emotions and behaviors of others in order to fit in.
  Despite their odd origins, some have opted to attempt to control them. It is currently unknown how this will end and what the repercussions may be.
  Psionics often report hearing dozens of minds crying out when they get near a voidborn, screaming to be released from their hell.
  There is some speculation that Voidborn are lesser fog demons but this is widely debated by imperial scholars and the Scribes' Guild.

  ## Biology

  Voidborn are a bit of an oddity in the sense that their biology appears to be a crude imitation of what an organic may look like.
  While they have fur, its texture is more akin to that of solidified air. Despite this fact, they remain very much solid.
  Voidborn have rather large eyes, being extremely sensitive to light. They are akin to glowing orbs rather than proper eyes, being a particular treasure of collectors and warlords.
  Externally, voidborn are androgynous with no difference or distinction between one or the other, leading to the general consensus they are all identical.
  Voidborn have four ears atop their head, although no scientific reason has been found for this development.
  Voidborn seem to lack the component in their brain which understands and translates emotion, their brain seemingly incomplete.

  ## Misc. Notes

  - Voidborn tend to be lighter than the average organic,  weighing in at just about 50kg. This is in stark contrast to the average organic's weight of 72kg, despite being the same size.

  ## Species Traits
  ### Positive Traits
  -[color=#303056]Void Crafted[/color]:
  Voidborn, as a result of having been crafted by an unknown entity, do not possess a pair of lungs and instead possess a core which replaces them. They seem to asphyxiate much slower than others as a result.

  -[color=#303056]Innate Telepathy[/color]:
  Voidborn are innately telepathic, allowing them to communicate with other psionic individuals at will.

  ### Negative Traits
  -[color=#303056]Incomplete Creation[/color]:
  Voidborn are very vulnerable to damage from an array of sources, preferring speed and agility over direct combat.

  -[color=#303056]Lightweight[/color]:
  Voidborn in general are not very heavy, rendering them easy to pick up and throw around.

  -[color=#303056]Unknown Origins[/color]:
  People hate what they don't know and Voidborn are the biggest mystery of them all. They will often be outright shot by the more suspicious folks in the sector.

</Document>
