<Document>
## LORE
A DSM punishment regimen, made up of disgraced soldiers and prisoners with too much experience to waste, runs a regular patrol of the Taypan sector.
Suddenly, their mass scanners detect a massive signature of an NCWL warfleet. The only remnants of a failed revolution. Your golden ticket out of punishment.
An inconvenient communications failure prevents them for signalling for help, and they decide try to regain their honor by stamping out the last embers of the revolution.

## OBJECTIVE
Each side's goal is to destroy the 3 Cloner Databases, henceforth reffered to as the objective, located on each fleet's warships.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UnionfallShipNodeNCWL" Caption="NCWL's Cloner Database"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UnionfallShipNodeDSM" Caption="DSM's Cloner Database"/>
</Box>

Either you can destroy them by direct and focused ship fire, or by going there in person interacting with it to sabotage.
Sabotaging takes 10 seconds, and rigs the objective to explode in 60 seconds. It can be disarmed as well.

## HADAL TIDE / GRACE PERIOD

At the start of the round, your main flagship (and the enemy's) is trapped inside an indestructible, immovable protective circle.
After a total of 20 minutes, the Hadal Tide ends and the circle dissipates. By this time, both teams should have ammassed a fleet of fighters and coherent squads.

## WHAT SHOULD YOU BE DOING?

1. Link up with your superior (the Knight-Bannaret, or the Grand Steward) and listen to their speech.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHatImperialBeret" Caption="look for this hat"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitImperialCommand" Caption="and this hardsuit"/>
</Box>
2a. Join with an existing ship crew and board their ship. Use a mass scanner to find docked Raiders or Jannissaries.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandHeldMassScannerEE" Caption="either use the scanner in your bag"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerRadar" Caption="or find this console"/>
</Box>

OR

2b. Get a ship LPC from a vendor
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NCWLConscriptShipVendory" Caption="vendor looks like this"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShipVoucherUnionfallKhopesh" Caption="you want this thing"/>
</Box>
3. Insert it in a shipyard console
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UnionfallClementineMothershipComputer" Caption="console looks like this"/>
</Box>
4. Use a mass scanner to find where it's docked
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandHeldMassScannerEE" Caption="either use the scanner in your bag"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerRadar" Caption="or find this console"/>
</Box>
5. Use your ID card (its in your PDA) to unlock the console
6. Go to the "Dock" section and undock to free up the space for the next ship

When the barrier falls, follow orders and do your best to maintain fleet cohesion. Good luck.

## DSM WARSHIP ROSTER

1. DSM Laelaps (two ships)
- Generalist war vessel, meant to do decently in all situations.
- Requires 1 pilot, 1 gunner and 1 loader.
- Front: 2x 120mm cannons, 2x plasmacasters
- Broadside: 3x "Needler" heavy autoguns, 1x "Jeong" swarmrocket platform
- Point Defense: 4x "Operator" machinegun turrets
- Frontal weaponry is well-equipped for long range harassment, but poorly suited for close range duelling
- Side-mounted autoguns are excellent for destroying heavy armor. Jeong launcher is good for destroying insides after hull is down.
- Operator turrets are good all-rounders for destroying ultralights and harassing fighters.

## DSM FIGHTER ROSTER

1. DSM Conquest
- An ultralight energy harasser with an EMP gun and a plasmacaster.
- Extremely fragile. Excels at disabling and slowly whittling down ships of all sizes.
- EMP gun saps the powergrid and disables electronics, while the plasmacaster offers dissapointing damage output. Bring a friend.
- DOES NOT HOLD ATMOSPHERE!

2. DSM Valor
- An ultralight energy bomber with an "Idna" dual torpedo launcher and a plasmacaster.
- Extremely fragile. Excels at hit-and-run attacks or finishing off retreating vessels.
- Idna torpedoes are homing and deal massive damage. Use them wisely!
- DOES NOT HOLD ATMOSPHERE!

3. DSM Ibis
- Mainline fighter. Decently armored. Equipped with an "Idna" dual torpedo launcher and dual plasmacasters.
- Side wings offer good protection and padding. Front cockpit is vulnerable.
- Idna torpedoes provide burst damage while plasma casters offer good sustained damage.

3. DSM Raider
- An unarmed, armored troop transport with an IFF cloaker for stealth.
- Very good top speed. Primary use is to sneak up on ships, dock, and kill crew in boarding combat.
- IFF cloaker, once activated, hides your signature from the Map screen (looks like a regular asteroid) and your nametag from the ship screen.
- Well armored except for the front shutters. Ideally don't get hit.

4. DSM Imparator
- A dedicated artillery boat with an explosive 120mm cannon, vulcan minigun, and two Point Defense Turrets.
- Requires a pilot AND a loader. Loader has access to a targeting console that controls PDT turrets.
- Small, mobile, and made to harass larger vessels. In this scenario, its gun devastates any vessel it manages to connect to.
- Plastitanium armor offers superior defence to other options.

</Document>
