<Document>
## LORE
After the destruction of their headquarters, Nova Belraska, the NCWL forces in Taypan flee for survival.
Their refuge is the Dear Clementine, a cargo freighter converted for war. A Gargut artillery carrier and Sasha heavy bomber follow suit.
A DSM warfleet detects their presence and moves to intercept. The fate of the revolution all hangs on this one battle.

## OBJECTIVE
Each side's goal is to destroy the 3 Cloner Databases, henceforth reffered to as the objective, located on each fleet's warships.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UnionfallShipNodeNCWL" Caption="NCWL's Cloner Database"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UnionfallShipNodeDSM" Caption="DSM's Cloner Database"/>
</Box>

Either you can destroy them by direct and focused ship fire, or by going there in person interacting with it to sabotage.
Sabotaging takes 10 seconds, and rigs the objective to explode in 60 seconds. It can be disarmed as well.

## HADAL TIDE / GRACE PERIOD

At the start of the round, your main flagship (and the enemy's) is trapped inside an indestructible, immovable protective circle.
After a total of 20 minutes, the Hadal Tide ends and the circle dissipates. By this time, both teams should have ammassed a fleet of fighters and coherent squads.

## WHAT SHOULD YOU BE DOING?

1. Link up with your superior (the Kommissar, or the Admiral) and listen to their speech.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHatNCWLKommissarHat" Caption="look for this hat"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterArmorNCWLCarapace" Caption="and this coat"/>
</Box>
2a. Join with an existing ship crew and board their ship. Use a mass scanner to find docked Lodkas or Vanguards.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandHeldMassScannerEE" Caption="either use the scanner in your bag"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerRadar" Caption="or find this console"/>
</Box>

OR

2b. Get a ship LPC from a vendor
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NCWLConscriptShipVendory" Caption="vendor looks like this"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShipVoucherUnionfallKhopesh" Caption="you want this thing"/>
</Box>
3. Insert it in a shipyard console
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UnionfallClementineMothershipComputer" Caption="console looks like this"/>
</Box>
4. Use a mass scanner to find where it's docked
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandHeldMassScannerEE" Caption="either use the scanner in your bag"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerRadar" Caption="or find this console"/>
</Box>
5. Use your ID card (it's in your PDA) to unlock the console
6. Go to the "Dock" section and undock to free up the space for the next ship
7. Perform pre-combat checks such as ensuring your weapons are loaded and ready to fire

When the barrier falls, follow orders and attempt to dock with the NT outpost. Good luck.

## NCWL WARSHIP ROSTER

1. NCWL Dear Clementine
- NCWL's flagship. Dwarfs most ships in Taypan in sheer size. Scares the rest with its arsenal.
- Front: 1x 320mm accelerator cannon
- Broadside: 4x Automortars
- Point Defense: Too much
- Spinal 320mm cannon is the most destructive weapon in the sector. If placed well, a single shot can disable most ships.
- Automortars offer incredible efficiency and destructive power at the cost of needing constant reloading.
- PDT is weak on it's own but en-masse it does not allow ultralights to even approach.

2. NCWL Gargut
- An artillery carrier with heavy armor and room padding.
- Front: 4 * 120mm artillery
- Front: 2 * Automortars
- Surrounding: 4 * "Slugspitter" 40mm guns
- Point Defense: Decent
- 120mm layout demands either 2 loaders, or to only use one side for repeated fire. Destructive power at range is second only to the 320mm.
- Automortars offer decent close range duelling power.
- Slugspitters and PDT turrets can hold their own against fighters from all directions, but not optimally.

3. NCWL Sasha
- Triple 230mm "Hephaestus" cannons on a slim hull. An ancient relic from another time.
- Front, and broadsides: 230mm "Hephaestus"
- PDT: Plenty
- 230mm cannon offers solid, long ranged destructive power with fast reloadable rounds. 
- PDT can harass fighters and delete ultralights, but it still requires escort to defend it properly.

## NCWL SHIP ROSTER

1. NCWL Broadsword
- An ultralight missle boat sporting dual Kurosawa launchers.
- Extremely fragile. Devastating when used as a hit-and-run vessel.
- Kurosawa launchers must be reloaded manually after expending their 2 shots.
- DOES NOT HOLD ATMOSPHERE!

2. NCWL Khopesh
- An ultralight gun boat sporting dual Vulcan miniguns.
- Extremely fragile. Excells at killing other ultralights, harassing ships and killing crew once hull is destroyed.
- Vulcan launchers each hold 500 rounds.
- DOES NOT HOLD ATMOSPHERE!

3. NCWL Lodka
- An armed and armored troop transport with an arsenal to defend itself.
- Armed with 2 Kurosawa launchers and 4 Point Defense Turrets. Launchers fired from pilot seat, PDTs fired from targeting console.
- Front is up-armored, rear is weak. Suffers from slow acceleration.

4. NCWL Vanguard
- An armored fighter made for extended engagements. Sports dual slugthrowers.
- Slugthrowers hold a low amount of ammo and must be manually reloaded (AND RACKED!) after emptying.
- Front is up-armored, rear is weak.

5. NCWL Aegis
- A modified Vanguard hull with a 120mm strapped in the middle.
- Requires 2 crew: 1 pilot and 1 loader/gunner.
- 120mm has long range and good damage, but requires constant reloading.
- Loader mans PDT while loading shells.


</Document>
