<Document>
## LORE
After the destruction of their headquarters, Nova Belraska, the NCWL homeguard flees for survival.
Their refuge is the Dear Clementine, a cargo freighter converted for war.
With many wounded, even more dead, and only an ancient pre-collapse armory to supply them, the remnants of the NCWL moves to lay claim to the abandoned Nanotrasen fuel outpost, Vladzena.

## OBJECTIVE
Each side's objective is to capture this experimental "Jamrock" shield generator, located on the southern side of NT Outpost Vladzena.
(If you see blood and rot spreading, then you're likely close.)

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UnionfallCapturePoint"/>
</Box>

It takes 10 seconds to activate, and then 10 minutes to finish once it's activated.
If captured after it is already activated, then 3 minutes are added to the timer.

## HADAL TIDE / GRACE PERIOD

At the start of the round, your main flagship (and the enemy's) is trapped inside an indestructible, immovable protective circle.
After a total of 20 minutes, the Hadal Tide ends and the circle dissipates. By this time, both teams should have ammassed a fleet and begun moving towards Vladzena.

## WHAT SHOULD YOU BE DOING?

1. Link up with your superior (the Kommissar, or the Admiral) and listen to their speech.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHatNCWLKommissarHat" Caption="look for this hat"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterArmorNCWLCarapace" Caption="and this coat"/>
</Box>
2a. Join with an existing ship crew and board their ship. Use a mass scanner to find docked Lodkas or Vanguards.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandHeldMassScannerEE" Caption="either use the scanner in your bag"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerRadar" Caption="or find this console"/>
</Box>

OR

2b. Get a ship LPC from a vendor
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NCWLConscriptShipVendory" Caption="vendor looks like this"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShipVoucherUnionfallKhopesh" Caption="you want this thing"/>
</Box>
3. Insert it in a shipyard console
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UnionfallClementineMothershipComputer" Caption="console looks like this"/>
</Box>
4. Use a mass scanner to find where it's docked
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandHeldMassScannerEE" Caption="either use the scanner in your bag"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerRadar" Caption="or find this console"/>
</Box>
5. Use your ID card (its in your PDA) to unlock the console
6. Go to the "Dock" section and undock to free up the space for the next ship

When the barrier falls, follow orders and attempt to dock with the NT outpost. Good luck.

## NCWL SHIP ROSTER

1. NCWL Broadsword
- An ultralight missle boat sporting dual Kurosawa launchers.
- Extremely fragile. Devastating when used as a hit-and-run vessel.
- Kurosawa launchers must be reloaded manually after expending their 2 shots.
- DOES NOT HOLD ATMOSPHERE!

2. NCWL Khopesh
- An ultralight gun boat sporting dual Vulcan miniguns.
- Extremely fragile. Excells at killing other ultralights, harassing ships and killing crew once hull is destroyed.
- Vulcan launchers each hold 500 rounds.
- DOES NOT HOLD ATMOSPHERE!

3. NCWL Lodka
- An armed and armored troop transport with an arsenal to defend itself.
- Armed with 2 Kurosawa launchers and 4 Point Defense Turrets. Launchers fired from pilot seat, PDTs fired from Targeting console.
- Front is up-armored, rear is weak. Suffers from slow acceleration.

4. NCWL Vanguard
- An armored fighter made for extended engagements. Sports dual slugthrowers.
- Slugthrowers hold a low amount of ammo and must be manually reloaded (AND RACKED!) after emptying.
- Front is up-armored, rear is weak.


</Document>
