<Document>
## LORE
A DSM punishment regimen, made up of disgraced soldiers and prisoners with too much experience to waste, runs a regular patrol of the Taypan sector.
Suddenly, their mass scanners detect a massive signature of an NCWL warship.
An inconvenient communications failure prevents them for signalling for help, and they decide try to regain their honor by stamping out the last embers of the revolution.

## OBJECTIVE
Each side's objective is to capture this experimental "Jamrock" shield generator, located on the southern side of NT Outpost Vladzena.
(If you see blood and rot spreading, then you're likely close.)

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UnionfallCapturePoint"/>
</Box>

It takes 10 seconds to activate, and then 10 minutes to finish once it's activated.
If captured after it is already activated, then 3 minutes are added to the timer.

## HADAL TIDE / GRACE PERIOD

At the start of the round, your main flagship (and the enemy's) is trapped inside an indestructible, immovable protective circle.
After a total of 20 minutes, the Hadal Tide ends and the circle dissipates. By this time, both teams should have ammassed a fleet and begun moving towards Vladzena.

## WHAT SHOULD YOU BE DOING?

1. Link up with your superior (the Marshal-Bannaret, or the Grand Steward) and listen to their speech.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHatImperialBeret" Caption="look for this hat"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitImperialCommand" Caption="and this hardsuit"/>
</Box>
2a. Join with an existing ship crew and board their ship. Use a mass scanner to find docked Raiders or Jannissaries.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandHeldMassScannerEE" Caption="either use the scanner in your bag"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerRadar" Caption="or find this console"/>
</Box>

OR

2b. Get a ship LPC from a vendor
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NCWLConscriptShipVendory" Caption="vendor looks like this"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShipVoucherUnionfallKhopesh" Caption="you want this thing"/>
</Box>
3. Insert it in a shipyard console
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UnionfallClementineMothershipComputer" Caption="console looks like this"/>
</Box>
4. Use a mass scanner to find where it's docked
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandHeldMassScannerEE" Caption="either use the scanner in your bag"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerRadar" Caption="or find this console"/>
</Box>
5. Use your ID card (its in your PDA) to unlock the console
6. Go to the "Dock" section and undock to free up the space for the next ship

When the barrier falls, follow orders and attempt to dock with the NT outpost. Good luck.

## DSM SHIP ROSTER

1. DSM Conquest
- An ultralight energy harasser with an EMP gun and a plasmacaster.
- Extremely fragile. Excels at disabling and slowly whittling down ships of all sizes.
- EMP gun saps the powergrid and disables electronics, while the plasmacaster offers dissapointing damage output. Bring a friend.
- DOES NOT HOLD ATMOSPHERE!

2. DSM Jannissary
- A penal fighter armed with a Slugthrower and a Sumitomo missle launcher.
- Well-rounded and decently mobile. Slugthrower offers decent consistent damage while Sumitomo devastates with burst damage.
- Slugthrower has a low ammo capacity and must be reloaded through a small spacewalk through the cockpit shutter.
- Sumitomo comes packed with only one 5 round magazine.
- Advised to bring a loader to assist with combat readiness.

3. DSM Raider
- An unarmed, armored troop transport with an IFF cloaker for stealth.
- IFF cloaker, once activated, hides your signature from the Map screen (looks like a regular asteroid) and your nametag from the ship screen.
- Well armored except for the front shutters. Either rely on the stealth or bring an escort crew.

4. DSM Imparator
- A dedicated artillery boat with an explosive 120mm cannon.
- Small, mobile, and made to harass larger vessels. In this scenario, its gun devastates any vessel it manages to connect to.
- Be wary of your limited armor and your slow fire rate.
- Extremely vulnerable to ultralights that catch up to it without support.


</Document>
