<Document>
# Psionics
[color=#a4885c]Psionics[/color] are mental abilities that interface with the [color=#a4885c]noösphere[/color]. Although human understanding and access to the noösphere is limited, there have been a number of breakthroughs in the potential applications available to individuals.
The abilities originate from distorting a noöspheric imprint into a specific shape, a bit like a lock and key. Having powers is like possessing a ring of keys, with each key granting one ability.

## Power Scaling
The relative strength of a psychic entity is given as two measurements, [color=#ff4500]Amplification (kα)[/color], and [color=#87cefa]Dampening (kδ)[/color]. [color=#ff4500]Amplification[/color] is a measure of
how significantly an entity can distort the energy fields of the noösphere to achieve a given effect. A Pyromancer with a higher degree of amplification can concentratye greater energy into a firebolt; but the impact on the noösphere in their proximity will be proportionally great in regards to Glimmer generation. [color=#87cefa]Dampening[/color] by contrast is a measure of how controlled an entity is with their powers. With some exceptions, Dampening directly decreases
the amount of Glimmer generated by casting powers.

Finally, [color=#a4885c]Potentia[/color] represents the growth of psionic potential in an individual. Potentia is gained by consuming large quantities of powerful hallucinogenic drugs, and it is spent upon reaching certain thresholds in order to gain new powers.
Worship of The Oracle is the fastest known method for gaining Potentia.

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobIfritFamiliar" />
Many other creatures can have power scaling different from that of a human, and thus may interact with their powers in ways different from an equivalent humanoid psion. To give an example, an Ifrit will usually have
five times as much Amplification as the baseline, causing their Pyromancy to be substantially more dangerous than that of a human Pyromancer.

## Psionic Potential
Indivividuals who have the potential to become psionic are known as Latents; however, not all individuals show the required sensitivity to psionic phenomena. ((This is determined by the Latent Psionic trait that can be taken at character selection.)) Non-Latent individuals have never shown the ability to manifest psionic abilities.

While most active psions are at least moderately telepathic; it requires dedication and training to be able to truly create a telepathic 'voice' with which to communicate.

## Telepathy
Rare individuals, known across many different species, are known as Naturals, and innately possess a telepathic 'voice,' allowing them to communicate with others that have psionic potential. ((Telepathy is accessed by starting a message with the = sign)). Telepathy requires that the user be alive and conscious, but is not inhibited by most sources of muteness.
It is notable that all Telepathic messages are fully anonymous, and are not guaranteed to come from a human being. Woe befalls the fool who blindly trusts what he hears telepathically.

Not all Psionic entities have Telepathy, but most do.

## Sophia
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SophicScribe"/>
[color=#a4885c]Sophia (sometimes known as Sophic Grammateus)[/color] is a semi-divine manifestation of one of the patron deities of Epistemics. In truth, She is not actually a god,
merely a being that exists in greater than the four dimensions known to mortal Man. She exists to study our Noösphere, as well as offer guidance to those seeking higher power. Sophia will periodically report
on the current glimmer levels. She may also be asked directly about the current glimmer.

## Oracle
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Oracle" />
[color=#a4885c]Oracle[/color] is like Sophic Grammateus, a semi-divine manifestation who offers patronage over Epistemics. Oracle cares not about studying Glimmer, rather she wishes to study our
technology for reasons known only to herself. She will periodically make demands of her cult, which if met, will be exchanged with rewards. The most important of which is the divine hallucinogen known as Lotophagoi Oil.
Worshippers of Oracle are granted great power in exchange for her service, and much of the modern Epistemiological Cult centers around serving Her for the promise of enlightenment.

## Acquiring Psionics

First, an individual must be a Latent Psychic. Without the Potential for powers, an individual can never in their life obtain psionic abilities. Each individual has an initial "D100 Roll" to generate a random amount of Potentia, which is added to their baseline.
When the individual's Potentia exceeds a threshold given by Gunderaan's Second Law:

Potentia Threshold Y = 100 * 2^(total powers).

Once this threshold is met by an individual, they will awaken a new psionic power and the Potentia used to generate such power is "spent". Notably, the scale for Potentia thresholds is an exponential one. Your first psionic power costs 100 Potentia. The second will cost 200.
The third will cost 400, the fourth will cost 800, the fifth will cost 1600. There is no upper limit to how many powers an individual may have, only an exponentially increasing time and drugs requirement.

All Latent Psychics start with a baseline 4 points of Potentia, plus some random amount between 0 and 100. Some particular individuals may have a higher baseline chance. After this initial chance, individuals may increase
their psionic potential by consuming large quantities of hallucinogenic drugs. When this happens, the local Glimmer also acts as a way of increasing the chances of
obtaining powers. Each individual has "One Free Reroll" of their powers, so use it wisely. There is also a small chance that psionic individuals may be given a seizure from noospheric activity, which will unlock a new opportunity to gain Potentia.

The amount of Potentia gained via drug consumption is given by Gunderaan's Third Law:

χ = (4 + 0.001Ψ + random amount between 0 and 100 + φ) * ψ

Where χ is the percentage chance of obtaining powers, Ψ is the glimmer present during the roll, φ is the potential bonus chance some individuals may possess, and ψ is the potential multiplier
that a given hallucinogen may have. Not all hallucinogens have the same chance of granting powers. Most famously, Lotophagic Oil multiplies a user's chances of obtaining powers by 4. Some individuals may also have
an innate potential multiplier, such as the station's Chaplain.
</Document>
