<Document>
  Be ware - this document is just almost a full copy of /tg/ station blood cult guide.

  # Blood Cult

  Even in the far future, some things are never quite understood. There are things that lurk in the darkness of space,
  unspeakable horrors of ancient power that wish to bring ruin to the universe and to shape it into their image. They
  reach out from the void, and turn the minds of mortal men and women in their favor in hopes that one day they shall be
  brought once more into this plane of existence.

  The Geometer of Blood, Nar-Sie, has sent a number of her followers to Space Station 14. As a cultist, you have an
  abundance of cult magics at your disposal, something for all situations. You must work with your brethren to summon an
  avatar of your eldritch goddess!

  ## Objectives

  Your objective requires you to sacrifice a certain crewmember and summon Nar-Sie.

  The general path of action of the cult and those in it:

  - 1. From a discrete location, contact your allies. You can do it by speaking Eldritch language - everyone in the cult
  can hear you when you speak it.
  - 2. Find an area to convert into a base, usually accessible by one or more members of the cult, but well-hidden
  enough that security or crew won't find it easily.
  - 3. Setup a teleport rune, so all cultists can access it.
  - 4. Setup an empowering rune and then prepare up to 4 blood spells. Stun spells are your bread and butter - but
  diversifying with spells like EMP, Teleport, Blood Rites, etc. will ensure you're ready for anything.
  - 5. Convert new members, or sacrifice implanted crew, on the offering rune. Combine the filled soul shard from
  sacrificed humans to create powerful cult constructs!
  - 6. Use teamwork to find your sacrifice target.
  - 7. Kill the sacrifice target and place them on an offer rune with 3 cultists nearby.
  - 8. Prepare to summon Nar-Sie. She can only be summoned in a few locations and the crew will fight desperately to
  stop you! Make sure you have enough cultists and equipment to withstand their assault.
  - 9. Gather 10 cultists on the final rune to summon Nar-Sie!

  ## Ritual Dagger

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RitualDagger" Caption="Ritual Dagger"/>
  </Box>

  Your dagger is your most important tool and has several functions:

  - You can draw runes with it.
  - Hitting a non-cultist with it will result in you stabbing them (huh), dealing 15 piercing damage.
  - Using it on the rune with erase it.
  - Using it on the cult barrier will remove it.

  ## Minor Runes

  These are minor runes cultists can draw anywhere on the station.

  <Box Orientation="Vertical" HorizontalAlignment="Center">
    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CultRuneOffering" Caption="Rune of Offering"/>
    </Box>
    Can be used to convert or sacrifice targets on it. It takes two cultists to convert someone.

    [bold]REMINDER: One cultist is required to sacrifice a dead body and three for a live one,
    standing adjacent to the rune. Each sacrifice will add to the Cult's total number of sacrifices, which are used
    to revive deceased bretheren instantly over a Revival Rune.[/bold]

    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CultRuneEmpower" Caption="Rune of Empower"/>
    </Box>
    Grants a buff allowing cultists to prepare greater amounts of blood magic at far less of a cost. While you have
    it, the spell count is capped at 4 instead of 1. Additionally, drawing runes takes far less time and you don't
    lose as much blood while doing it.

    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CultRuneTeleport" Caption="Rune of Teleportation"/>
    </Box>
    This rune warps everything above it to another teleport rune when used. Creating a teleport rune will allow you to
    set a tag for it.

    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CultRuneRevive" Caption="Rune of Rejuvenation"/>
    </Box>
    Placing a cultist corpse on the rune and activating it will bring them back to life. Consumes one charge on use
    and starts with three freebie revivals, so use it sparingly. .

    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CultRuneBarrier" Caption="Rune of Barrier"/>
    </Box>
    When invoked, makes a temporary barrier to block passage.

    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CultRuneSummoning" Caption="Rune of Summoning"/>
    </Box>
    This rune allows you to instantly summon any living cultist to the rune, consuming it afterward. Does not work on
    restrained cultists who are buckled or being pulled.

    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CultRuneBloodBoil" Caption="Rune of Boiling Blood"/>
    </Box>
    When invoked, it saps some health from the invokers to send three damaging pulses to anyone who can see the
    rune and ignites them.
  </Box>

  ## Major runes

  These are the major runes cultists can draw once they meet certain conditions. They need a free 3x3 space, and can only
  be summoned in 3 areas around the station (or have 3 global charges). Depleting all of them makes you unable to draw
  them anymore. So be careful not to consume all of them with apocalypse runes or you'll never be able to summon
  Nar'Sie!

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CultRuneApocalypse" Caption="Rune of Apocalypse"/>
  </Box>

  A harbinger of the end times. It scales depending on the crew's strength relative to the cult. Effect includes a
  massive EMP, total blackout, solar flare and if the cult is doing poorly, certain events. If the cult makes up to
  less than 15% of current players, and an apocalypse rune is activated, a random event will
  occur:
  - Immovable Rod x3
  - Mouse Migration x2
  - Meteor Swarm x2
  - Vent Crickets x3
  - Four Random Anomalies
  - Kudzu Growth x2
  - Vendor Mimics x2

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CultRuneDimensionalRending" Caption="Rune of Dimensional Rending"/>
  </Box>
  This rune tears apart dimensional barriers, calling forth the Geometer. To start drawing it the requested target
  must have already been sacrificed. Starting to draw this rune alarms the entire station of its location. The caster
  must be defended for 45 seconds before it's complete.
  After it's drawn, 10 cultists, constructs, or summoned ghosts must stand on the rune, which can then be invoked to
  manifest Nar'Sie itself.

  ## Blood Spells

  Blood Spells are limited-use blood magic spells that dissipate after they're spent, and they're your bread and butter
  when fighting the crew. Blood Spells can be created at any time via a menu when right clicking your character.
  However, blood spells created without an Empowering Rune will take longer, cause significant blood loss, and
  will cap your spell count at a measly one

  A good tip is to make sure to try and have a stun spell and a teleport spell with you to escape risky situations. This
  will leave only two other options for spells though, so carefully choose what you think might help best for a
  particular situation.


  ## Constructs

  Shades and constructs are slaved to their masters will. They must follow the orders of their master at any cost. They
  are capable of grasping intent, unlike synthetic beings. Constructs created by cultists automatically become cultists
  themselves, allowing them to identify their team mates, and even count for the escape objective.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShadeCult" Caption="Shade"/>
  </Box>
  Shades are fragile, but being recaptured into their soul shard heals them. Useful if you quickly need someone to help
  you activate a rune.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ConstructArtificer" Caption="Artificer"/>
  </Box>
  The artificer is the "drone" of the cult. It can construct cult-floors, walls and reinforced walls, as well as take
  apart the station, but its main purpose is to provide the materials to construct additional constructs. It can create
  new soul stones or shells after a certain time.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ConstructWraith" Caption="Wraith"/>
  </Box>
  The wraith is a tiny bit more fragile than a human but has a strong melee attack. It can become invisible and travel
  through closed doors and even walls by using it's phase shift ability.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ConstructJuggernaut" Caption="Juggernaut"/>
  </Box>
  Juggernauts are strong, slow and have lots of health. They can destroy any wall by simply punching it and do more
  damage than Wraiths. They cannot be pushed or grabbed and even have a force-wall ability similar to the wizard spell.

  ## Tips
  - Only cultists can know a rune's name and effects by examining it.
  - Always be ready to summon a cultist in trouble. You can't summon them if they're already cuffed.
  - Keeping a shade in a Soulstone Shard with you will allow you to use two-person runes by yourself, by releasing and
  then recapturing the shade.
  - Cultists often find a use for medibots. Having a single bot with a low threshold, backed up by brutepacks or pylons,
  can keep your cult in fighting shape.
  - The EMP spell and Apocalypse Rune are both incredibly useful. They can give you access almost anywhere, just don't
  forget your crowbar!
</Document>
