<Document>
  # Shadowlings
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookShadowling" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  They aren't gods. But they want to become one...
  These enigmatic aliens have baffled even the most advanced research divisions.

  Shadowlings are light-sensitive xenoform alien creatures that come from space.
  Primarily defensive in nature, they possess the ability to [bold]enthrall[/bold] crew members, taking full control of their minds and loyalty.

  Shadowlings starts off disguised as a normal crew member.
  After they awake, they must 'hatch' to unlock their powers.

  When hatched, shadowlings will resemble humans with black skin, small horns, red eyes, and claws.

  Shadowlings can not shoot guns, or wear clothes of any kind. Despite that, they can still equip headsets.

  As a side-note, Shadowlings are not obliged to work together. While cooperation may help, going solo is a valid play-style.

  ## What do I do as a Shadowling?

  As a shadowling, your main objective is to [color=#d22b2b]ascend[/color].

  In order to ascend, you'll have to:
  - 1. Gather 20 Thralls.
  - 2. Form your Ascension Egg using your "Ascendance" ability.
  - 3. Enter the egg and begin the ascension ritual

  You are vulnerable to light and will take damage while exposed. However, [bold]you heal in the shadows[/bold], so use darkness to your advantage.

  Initially, you start with +50% resistance from light, but the more crew you enthrall, the less the resistance becomes.
  It can go up to -50%! That's a lot of damage you'll be taking...

  Choose your Thralls wisely.

  ## I'm a thrall, what is my purpose?

  You're similar to a revolutionary— but with time and obedience, you can become something far more powerful.

  As a thrall, your main purpose is to listen to your shadowling, the one that converted you.
  If your shadowling demands that you suicide, you must suicide. It doesn't matter if you're a Wizard or a Nukie.

  You also have a few abilities at your disposal, like Guise and Thrall Darksight.

  - Guise: Grants temporary invisibility when used in the dark.

  - Thrall Darksight: Grants night vision, allowing you to see in complete darkness.

  The more obedient and useful you are, the more valuable you become to your Shadowling.

  ## What can I do as crew to fight against the shadowlings?

  A shadowling is a threat that should be taken care of early in the shift.

  - Never patrol maintenance alone. Stick to groups.
  - Security should stay armed and alert.

  Nanotrasen has also issued the Mantis with a special device that essentially took several decades of researching this
  strange alien species and its effects on living beings.

  The [bold]anti-mind control device[/bold] can remove any mind control from any person, and apply further resistance to the Thrall
  that is to be deconverted.

  It exists in Tier 2 research through the prolathe and it has the same materials as a Flash, but with Lead required.

  Don't forget that it has only [bold]5 charges[/bold] per device.

  Other than that, note that Lesser Shadowlings are not affected from it. Their mind is lost, and sadly unrecovable.

  Additional Countemeasures:
  - Mindshield implants offer temporary protection, though Shadowlings will gain abilities to bypass them.
  - Psionic insulation fully prevents mind control and is highly recommended.

  In case of a shadowling starting an ascension, all available crew should arm themselves and rush to destroy the ascension egg before the process completes.
  Succeed, and you live. Fail... and witness a god!

  ## How do I ascend?

  Once you have 20 thralls, use your "Ascendance" ability to place your ascension egg.
  Right-click the egg and select "Start Ascension".

  You will be immobile and vulnerable for 5 minutes during the process.

  If the egg is destroyed, you become an Abomination. That means:
    - No powers
    - Extremely slow movement
    - Practically useless

  Protect your egg at all costs. Failure means humiliation.

  ## What happens if a Shadowling ascends...

  If a shadowling ascends, there's still a chance to win by killing the shadowling. However, it has a good amount
  of health (around the same as a Space Dragon) and very strong abilities.

  Once an ascension completes, all shadowlings will ascend at a moment's notice and Thralls will be turned into Nightmares.

  Nightmares have arm-blades that can ash lights, and they can phase through walls without a care in the world!

  Nightmares also reflect bullets when in the dark.

  ## What is a Lesser Shadowling?

  A lesser shadowling is a thrall who got converted by the Black Recuperation ability.
  Lesser Shadowlings can not be deconverted by the anti-mind control device.

  However, they do take damage from lights, similarly to a Shadowling. Much slower, though.

  You can have up to 5 of them, so choose them carefully. Quality over quantity.

  ## Tips and more info

  - As a shadowling, you can identify your thralls by examining them.

  - Even though other shadowlings will ascend once one ascends, it may be more fun to have
  competition. Be the only ascendant, or die trying...

  - Your Collective Mind ability paralyzes your Thralls once you gain a new power. However, it also
  informs you on how many thralls you need to ascend.

  - Examine yourself to see how much light resistance you have.

  - Black Recuperation decreases your light resistance per use, so be careful when you use it.

  [bold][color=#000000]Become the darkness.[/color] [color=#702963]Embrace the void.[/color] [color=#D2042D]Ascend.[/color][/bold]

</Document>
