<Document>
  ## Help! I have a slime on my face!
  Just pull it or ask someone to apply xenovac on you.
  Otherwise you can just kill it.

  # Xenobiology
  Xenobiology is the breeding and harvesting of slimes and their extracts for scientific purposes.
  This all takes place in the xenobiology lab where you spawn, and is arguably more dangerous than researching artifacts if you don't know what you are doing.
  Which is a good reason to read this!

  ## What does a xenobiologist do?
  Shortly speaking: feed slime -> wait for slime to grow -> wait for slime to split -> kill slime -> grind slime -> sell it for profit.

  ## Feeding
  Slimes eat EVERYTHING. Nutribricks, pizza, you name it.
  And yes, even the Clown.
  They can latch onto other mobs to start slowly consuming their flesh.
  One monkey provides enough nutrients for a slime to grow into an adult.

  #### Pro tip: Do NOT enter the pen and bash the monkey, the only thing that will happen is slime will get less food.

  Once they're fed enough, after a while the adult slime will split in 1-4 baby slimes.
  And once you've had them split enough to fill two whole departments, you can move onto the next step.

  #### Pro tip: Pet the slime to tame it. Tamed slimes won't try to latch onto you unless VERY hungry. They also retain their tameness after splitting!

  ## Culling
  Time to kill your darlings.
  Decide which baby slimes you don't want to keep and proceed to apply heavy doses of "fire extinguisher" to their face.
  Water is most effective in slime murder, but basic head bashing also gets the job done.
  The sheer amount of shower will almost immediately kill a slime.
  When they turn into a pancake, they're dead and you can pick them up for the next step.

  ## Grinding
  Drag the dead slimes on top of a slime grinder. It will automatically start and drop a slime core after some time.
  These cores can be injected with any reagent using a syringe, but will violently react only with specific ones.
  This is usually plasma, water and blood, but you can check them using your slime scanner.

  ## Extracts
  As of now there is no specific official cheat sheet of what all the slime extracts can possibly do, so experiment!

  # So, you're a Traitor
  There's a LOT of extracts that could benefit you. Free EMPs, pacifiers, speed potions and such.
  This guide does not include an entry on extracts, and probably never will, but here are some hints:
  - Yellow can cause EMPs and explode.
  - Red can give you a speed coating for your clothing and make nearby mobs rabid.
  - Sepia is funny.
  - Gold extract is just outright evil.

  The rest is up to you to figure out!
</Document>
