<Document>
    All Information included in this document is licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0, and is taken from https://wiki.aurorastation.org/index.php?title=Einstein_Engines with some modifications.

    # Einstein Engines

    - [bold]Slogan:[/bold] [italic] Lead by our history, leading our future[/italic]
    - [bold]Headquarters:[/bold] Harmony City, Luna, Sol
    - [bold]Official Languages:[/bold] Tau-Ceti Basic, Sol Common, Tradeband
    - [bold]Official Colours:[/bold] [color=#777700]Olive Green (#777700)[/color], [color=#637C65]Sage Green (#637C65)[/color], [color=#DFE4ED]White (#DFE4ED)[/color], [color=#AB6F19]Orange (#AB6F19)[/color]
    - [bold]Founded:[/bold] 2155 by the Standard Sol Calendar.
    - [bold]Founder:[/bold] Zhong Hu
    - [bold]Notable Branches:[/bold] Taipei Engineering Industrial, Terraneus Diagnostics

    Founded in Sol during the 2100s, Einstein Engines is a trans-stellar megacorporation that focuses on both warp travel technology and robotics,
    and is said to have a monopoly on the former. Headed by the cutthroat Noelle Lopez-Zhang, Einstein Engines has found itself having been through
    a combination of rigorous technological improvements in their warp drive designs that have found the megacorporation at an advantage due to the shortages of Phoron
    across the Orion Spur, as well as careful expansion and dominance within the now collapsed Solarian Alliance.
    Considered an antagonist to the goals of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate,
    Einstein Engines has managed on multiple occasions to outperform the corporations beneath its banner and continues to improve as each day passes.

    ## History

    Einstein Engines originated as a conglomerate of various aerospace companies who shared a joint research project for extrastellar travel.
    As the project came into fruition, it was realized it would have immense consequences for the human race.
    In the year 2130, a sustained, stable warp interface was formed. This development served to catapult the conglomerate to be a dominating economic
    power across Sol. Their warp technology revolutionized space travel and led to the construction of micro-g orbital industrial stations around the equator.
    This boom in industrial capabilities led to the great expansion of humanity across space. Warp-enabled probes traveled to nearby systems,
    finding habitable worlds scattered across space. The power of Einstein Engines continued to grow throughout the following centuries,
    eclipsing other interstellar corporations; however, this expansion was not to last.

    In 2417, a relatively young corporation, Nanotrasen, discovered a previously unknown material known as Phoron,
    a substance with incredible energy density, far beyond that of conventional fusion or fission.
    This energy source, along with the advent of the Skrell experimental, though superior, Bluespace drives burst the unending growth bubble of Einstein Engines.
    As Nanotrasen grew into the present-day superpower it is, Einstein Engines fell inwards. Major restructuring was done to save the company,
    leading to its modern form.

    Today, Einstein Engines still holds a significant power base despite the losses in the first half of the 25th century.
    Continuing to serve its market, Einstein Engines produces many important spaceship components and continues to contend
    with Nanotrasen over the efficiency of their different marques of Bluespace engine. The two giants awkwardly co-exist in human space,
    with multiple copyright and trademark lawsuits bouncing between them on a monthly basis.

    As the phoron crisis began to worsen the conflict between Nanotrasen and Einstein Engines only began to heat up,
    with EE managing to successfully defend itself against NT in a massive legal battle, as well as purchase the Biesel city of
    Phoenixpoint from NT, with EE planning a massive restoration of the city. Due to their conflict with NT
    Einstein Engines has elected not to support or join the SCC, being famously the only of the major megacorporations not to do so.

    To fight against the consolidation of power between the other major megacorporations with the establishment of the
    SCC Einstein Engines has begun to seek trade partners in areas outside the influence the SCC, most notably the Nralakk Federation,
    with EE managing to secure a contract to establish their Qerrbalak Branch.

    ## Influence
    Einstein Engines wields considerable influence within the Sol Alliance, being founded more than three hundred years ago.
    Its established reputation in the manufacturing of ship components and warp technology has solidified its place,
    allowing it to survive as other corporations such as NanoTrasen continue to expand rapidly across the Spur.
    Outside of the Sol Alliance, Einstein has made some progress in Tau Ceti with its recent acquisition of Phoenixport
    and is currently revitalising the city as part of its plans for future operations within the system.
    Einstein Engines has also made leeway with the Nralakk Federation and their Special Economic Zones,
    winning the Qerrbalak contract over NanoTrasen and establishing a branch office there.
    Despite its smaller operational scope compared to other megacorporations,
    its marketing of warp technology as a safer and more cost-effective alternative to bluespace travel,
    combined with its reputation as a reliable manufacturer, has allowed the company to have at least some influence across most of human space.

    The megacorporation also holds considerable sway in the field of artificial intelligence.
    Although its competitors would never admit it, Einstein Engines consistently produces the most advanced positronic brains,
    with many of their models surpassing and eclipsing that of other companies.
    Furthermore, they remain the second-largest producer of positronic brains in the Spur,
    providing for customers in the Sol Alliance as well as the Coalition.
    The company also has lucrative defence contracts with the Sol Alliance, not only providing AI and engines for the Sol Navy but IPCs as well,
    serving in both combat and non-combat roles. With relations between the Conglomerate and the Alliance at a record low,
    Einsteins hold over the market can only grow.

    ## Internal Reputation

    Despite the common beliefs in the Republic of Biesel, the megacorporation is deemed as a fair employer with plenty of benefits, such as a full health plan, including dental care, and up to two weeks of vacation per year. Company cars are a common benefit amongst most members above a certain rank, and a healthy fraternal work environment is promoted. Those individuals that have worked with Nanotrasen before their employment in Einstein Engines will often quote these benefits as their main reason to change companies.

    While some may say that these features are due to the progressive work laws in the Sol Alliance, the standard was set by Einstein Engines shortly after a bonanza period, following the discovery of the warp engine. For Einstein Engines, their employees require to have their necessities covered so they can be happier and more productive.

    In the 25th century, the megacorporation has seen some setbacks due to the new phoron travel. As a consequence, the salaries remain more or less on par with those of their competitors, despite traditionally being higher. Nevertheless, the opportunity to grow inside the company and multiple bonuses offered per month, if a job is done right, still make up for these losses.

    ## Positronics and Einstein Engines

    Einstein Engines is one of the largest manufacturers of positronics within the Spur through their subsidiary Terraneus Diagnostics, the original creators of the positronic brain complex and shell IPC frame who maintains a large market share of both with a focus on the higher end of quality.

    Einstein Engines makes extensive use of synthetics within its corporate structure, however, synthetics are barred from holding leadership roles, be it that of managers in corporate facilities or commanders onboard corporate ships. Instead, synthetics are largely seen as tools to be used by organic employees. This attitude stems from Einstein Engines' heavy involvement with the Sol Alliance, as their view on synthetics is identical to that of the Alliance government. The company makes use of their own high end shell frames and cheaper, more available baseline frames primarily, though others are occasionally bought from other megacorporations.

    Synthetics owned by Einstein Engines are normally worked to the limit within their assigned position and are expected to greatly outperform organic employees due to their cost, and punishments such as memory wipes, retooling or scrapping are always on the table. That being said, Einstein Engines pursues a “quality over quantity” philosophy with their IPC, only using harsher methods such as memory wipes for repeat offenders. The company views the experience an older IPC might gain as having a value of its own.

    Freedom is only offered to synthetics in areas that require it to be an option, such as Biesel or Konyang, otherwise, they will be offered no legal chance at achieving it by the company and scrapping is often used to retire synthetics rather than selling them, although special treatment is given to its close partners and employees, who are often approached with an offer first. Attempts of synthetics to escape to freedom are not unheard of within the corporation, and those caught are immediately scrapped as punishment.

    It is expected for Shells owned by Einstein Engines to use simple one or two syllable first names such as “Joe” or “Robert” whilst other frames used by the company use the name format “EES-(Name/Designation)” where “EES” stands for Einstein Engines Synthetic.

    # Relations to Other Corporations

    ## Hephaestus Industries
    Einstein is a major competitor for Hephaestus in the field of IPC manufacturing - in spite of this, however, the two megacorporations have long had a close working relationship, particularly in the Solarian shipbuilding industry. Many Hephaestus-manufactured civilian and military vessels in Sol are equipped with Einstein-made warp drives, especially after the refitting of the Solarian Navy to the Suzuki-Zhang Hammer Drive. If Hephaestus's membership in the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate has been a source of tension between the two megacorporations, little sign of this has been shown openly, with the industrial giant continuing to work with Einstein on many of its Solarian assets. Rumors of Einstein providing ships and weaponry to groups such as the Exclusionists in the region around Burzsia - or of Hephaestus-backed privateers targeting Einstein vessels in the former Human Wildlands - remain only rumors, and have had little impact on the two companies' shared business.

    ## Idris Incorporated
    Idris and Einstein have a generally positive relationship, with little need for competition. The vast majority of Idris-owned Shell IPCs are manufactured by Einstein, and their robotics division has allegedly developed several enhanced combat modifications for higher-end Idris Reclamation Units. Idris vessels tend to favor Einstein-produced warp drives over NanoTrasen-produced bluespace drives, with the exception of some of their higher-end security vessels and luxury yachts which advertise speed of travel as a major bonus. Following Solarian nationalization efforts, Idris and Einstein are the two most influential corporations in the Alliance, with Idris having paid high fees to avoid nationalization of its assets. This has given the two corporations a mutual goal - maintaining their own prominence in Solarian affairs, and ensuring that future anti-corporate legislation remains directed at their rivals. Einstein and Idris have both heavily invested in their own PR within the Alliance, remaining invested in Sol's future development.

    ## NanoTrasen
    NanoTrasen and Einstein have been rivals for decades, since the discovery of phoron in 2417 and the subsequent invention of the bluespace drive. As bluespace largely superseded warp as a means of faster-than-light travel, NanoTrasen's power rose as Einstein's waned. Since then, the two companies have been fierce competitors, contending in court constantly over various trademarks, patents, and other legal issues. The phoron scarcity beginning in 2462 has led to a reversal of fortunes, with Einstein rising massively in prominence as NanoTrasen's power fades - leading NanoTrasen to spearhead the formation of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate to attempt to combat their old rivals. The two corporations continue to clash to this day, with Einstein having found a foothold in the city of Phoenixport, Biesel - setting up shop in the heart of NanoTrasen's power. Though Einstein holds the clear advantage for now, NanoTrasen has worked tirelessly to try and slow the meteoric growth of their rival corporation - so far, to little effect, as phoron prices continue to rise and NanoTrasen stock prices continue to fall.

    ## Orion Express
    Einstein Engines and Orion have had little in the way of a working relationship, with the shipping corporation being formed largely from assets of their rivals at NanoTrasen. Einstein has reportedly advocated extensively for subjecting Orion to the same nationalization as faced by the other SCC corporations in the Sol Alliance - though so far to little effect, as Orion continues to operate freely within Solarian space. Outside of Sol, however, Einstein makes frequent use of Orion's shipping services, particularly within the Republic of Biesel and the Nralakk Federation - two nations where Orion is able to transport goods far more freely than Einstein.

    ## Zavodskoi Interstellar
    Einstein Engines and Zavodskoi have a fairly neutral relationship - though the two do compete in the robotics sector, Zavodskoi has purchased many Einstein-made warp drives for its vessels over the years, and the two have both had generous supply contracts with the Solarian military in the past. In the modern day, Zavodskoi has lost a great deal of these contracts, while Einstein continues to hold many highly valuable government and military contracts - a factor which contributed to Zavodskoi's withdrawal of much of its Solarian business. In spite of this, it continues to purchase warp drives from Einstein frequently, due to the rising cost of phoron fuel and the easy availability of helium-3 from Zavodskoi's new home in the Empire of Dominia.

    ## Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals
    The relationship between Zeng-Hu and Einstein is a generally positive one, with the two corporations cooperating extensively in several areas of mutual interest - their operations on the planet Konyang and mutual desire for expansion within the Nralakk Federation being the most noteworthy among these. Though Zeng-Hu's membership in the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate and Einstein's growing power within the Sol Alliance has led to a level of distrust between the two, their relationship has remained largely solid since the beginning of the phoron shortage. In 2466, Einstein and Zeng-Hu were both called upon by the government of Konyang to deal with the rampancy crisis, with Zeng-Hu's involvement leading to the wider Conglomerate working to address the problem.

    ## Spinward Fringe Syndicate
    Despite sharing a common enemy in NanoTrasen, there is no love lost between Einstein Engines and the Syndicate. The Syndicate perceives Einstein Engines to be
    not significantly different from NanoTrasen. The Syndicate believes that were Einstein Engines to gain a significant advantage over NanoTrasen, fate has it
    that Einstein Engines would be the Syndicate's primary target instead. Einstein in turn views the Syndicate as a force fundamentally incompatible with their business dealings.
</Document>
