<Document>
    All Information included in this document is licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0, and is taken from https://wiki.aurorastation.org/index.php?title=Hephaestus_Industries with some modifications.

    # Hephaestus Heavy Industries

    - [bold]Slogan:[/bold] [italic]The anvil on which the world is shaped[/italic]
    - [bold]Headquarters:[/bold] Cua Song, New Hai Phong, Sol Alliance
    - [bold]Official Languages:[/bold] Freespeak, Tau-Cetic Basic, Sol Common, Sinta'Unathi
    - [bold]Official Colours:[/bold] [color=#ab6f19]Orange (#ab6f19)[/color], [color=#263e23]Green (#263e23)[/color]
    - [bold]Founded:[/bold] 2137 by the Standard Sol Calendar.
    - [bold]Founder:[/bold] Robert Claremont
    - [bold]Notable Branches:[/bold] Xion Manufacturing Group, notable alliances with the Izweski Hegemony.

    Hephaestus Industries is one of the most prominent megacorporations within the Orion Spur. They are responsible for a large majority of the trans-stellar factions manufacturing capabilities, having facilities in the Coalition of Colonies, Republic of Biesel, Izweski Nation, and several other frontier colonies. They have managed to secure themselves a stable foundation, continually growing even in the face of the Solarian Collapse, Phoron Scarcity, and the supposed inevitable economic recession that stares the Orion Spur in the face. They make considerable contributions to the field of robotics, as well as starship research and development.

    ## History

    Originally founded in the year 2137, seven years after the advent of Warp technology, Hephaestus Aeronautics was formed out of a conglomeration of several failing aerospace companies. They combined their assets and expertise in an attempt to retain a niche in the FTL market. With humanity in a growing state of expansion and exploration, Hephaestus profits by designing and selling warp drives, with heavy competition between themselves and Einstein Engines.

    When the Second Great Depression struck in 2260, Hephaestus had no other option than to file for many massive bailouts. Barely saving their company from the pit of bankruptcy, they shifted their focus from warp travel to industrialization. As the years passed, they secured more and more industrial centres from many other small producers, both land-based and orbital. Recognizing Hephaestus’s presence along with the growing unrest in the frontier at the time, the Sol Alliance promised them commissions for providing them with machines of war; starships, arms, and armour. Hephaestus gladly obliged. Every handful of years, another smaller production company, and their assets are seized by Hephaestus. By 2400, Hephaestus Industries had become the number one producer in all of the inner colonies, owning almost one hundred percent of the heavy industry. Owning two gargantuan orbital factories in the Sol system, and another under construction in Tau Ceti, it was clear who the industrial powerhouse of Humanity was. Nanotrasen was quick to step up to the plate, however, and when they claimed the rights to the Romanovich cloud and discovered the pivotal resource Phoron, Hephaestus was forced to find another avenue of profit once again.

    After the discovery of the Skrell, and the introduction of artificial intelligence, Hephaestus began shifting its research focus from mineral processing and engine design to robotics. Dedicating several research stations to this project resulted in their facilities, mainly their factories, being overhauled to remove unnecessary systems and make way for streamlined central intelligence cores, as well as dedicating several lines of production to the creation of commercialized workforce robots.

    After the discovery of the Unathi, and the ascension of the Izweski Nation to the galactic stage, NanoTrasen as a corporation withdrew from the fledgling nation state, focusing instead on matters closer to humanity. Hephaestus filled this vacuum left by NanoTrasen, becoming the only Megacorporation to have a Hegemonic Guild Charter, which allowed them to operate within the nation. After years of floundering attempting to adapt to an antiquated feudal system of guilds used by the Hegemony, Hephaestus eventually stabalized, having adapted to the Guild system with the help of Yukal T’zakal, who was at the time sector administrator for the Hegemony. Slowly but surely the corporation worked its way into influencing the nation, until in 2465, in the midst of the phoron scarcity, it played its winning hand. Bailing out the rest of the Hegemonic Guilds in exchange for them becoming subsidiaries of Hephaestus Industries, the megacorporation gained a monopoly over the economy of the small nation, all while still in the name of helping it.

    The unveiling of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate saw Hephaestus Industries as one of its prominent members, being the backbone of the colossal interstellar corporation’s heavy industry and adding to its fleets through Hephaestus Industries’ massive industrial division - however, the lack of cooperation with Einstein Engines has reduced productivity and forced the megacorporation to work with NanoTrasen and Zavodskoi Interstellar to recreate sub-light, warp drives and bluespace drives with diminished efficiency.

    Today, Hephaestus Industries is the largest provider of heavy industry for the Orion Spur, led by the charismatic and firm CEO Titanius Aeson. From New Hai Phong to Burzia, and now all the way to Tret, their factories ceaselessly work, constantly producing anything and almost everything used in the modern day. They are also supported by an advanced robotics division that produces new technology for artificial intelligence and commercialized robots for the working and military world. Recently, Hephaestus Industries has pledged to bring forth another wave of colonization of the frontier and promises support for struggling colonies. This isn’t coming from the bottoms of their hearts, of course. These colonies would be bound to provide resources to Hephaestus in trade for the company’s support.

    ## Influence

    Hephaestus Industries is the largest blanket commodity manufacturer in the known universe. Its reach extends across the Orion Spur and virtually all modern, and often antique, utilities owe their creation to it. It is the most sought-after fabricator of heavy-duty industrial equipment and starships.

    The sheer power of Hephaestus’s Influence can be seen most clearly in the Izweski Nation where Hephaestus has a stranglehold monopoly over the nation's economy, being the only legal exporter and importer, as well as holding all the Izweski Nation’s production in it’s fist. Everything that requires more than feudal peasants to produce, maintain, or construct is operated by Hephaestus Industries and its subsidiary companies.

    With Aeson's rise to the forefront, Hephaestus Industries as a workforce is the embodiment of the common worker, the family man, and loyalty to the company like a second family. As such, they are inclusive to every species, welcoming anyone willing to join the family, while "rewarding" hard and gritty work typically delegated to species besides humans and Skrell: these species are usually put in supervisory and logistics roles. Despite this, the intense loyalty of Unathi as a species and their strong sense of honor and family have made them quick favourites among the company, lending them to a rise of their own. Regardless of where you work, expect a generous benefits package in return: paid vacation time, sick leave, company insurance for on- and off-site protection, and a myriad of more localized items.

    The corporate structure works to the benefit of employees as well. Those that buy stock in the company and work from within, regardless of position, not only should expect the typical dividends that come with it, but also increased benefits that come on top of existing ones. Hephaestus is almost seen as a marvel when it comes to this. Supervisors often play up the worth of these shares and actively talk about them in more casual settings, authorizing an atmosphere of encouraging workers to buy into the company. The result is a single stock being worth much more than it probably is— and being unobtainable for most people on the bottom rung of the corporate ladder.

    Hephaestus is not without its flaws, however. Their generosity is often weaponized against its workers, claiming that disloyalty to the company is its biggest enemy. Supervisors actively encourage people to rat out others trying to unionize or otherwise undermine the company to encourage loyalty on the foreman's floor. Similarly, those found talking about the "Himeo" or "New Hai Phong Problems" typically find themselves summarily fired with a meagre severance package. Despite this, or perhaps because of all of this, they remain one of the largest and influential corporations in the Orion Spur.

    Additionally, Hephaestus has begun to score a nasty reputation as being the most destructive corporation for planet ecosystems. Himeo being perhaps the most egregious example, this megacorporation is willing to go to whatever ends it requires in order to keep the rust belt rolling. Other planets that find themselves catching up to this state of affairs include New Hai Phong, Eridani I, Burzsia, and more recently, Ouerea. Yet many more are finding their way towards being a new smog-covered member of this factory family. To make matters worse, Hephaestus gives little regard to the people of the planet in these positions outside of the company; Eridani I's denizens have to buy their own filtered air and masks when traversing the surface, and New Hai Phongers typically claustrophobia and asthma from the overcrowded and terrible air conditions on the planet.

    To put things simply, Hephaestus Industries is a unique case among corporations where respect and loyalty play a major role in climbing the ranks. One must earn their ties by ratting out others, investing in the company, or otherwise proving their loyalty to make any sort of drastic leap, making it a very linear corporate ladder. The higher ranking an individual is, the older they ought to be, with major executives either being the eldest among them. In this sense, Hephaestus is seen as the sturdiest foundation civilization has ever constructed with so much in the way of trust and age-old wisdom, their simple pursuit of corporate greed has, at least publicly, been long reformed into one of peace and prosperity.

    ## Positronics and Hephaestus Industries
    Hephaestus Industries exercises vast authority over the second-hand production of almost all Integrated Positronic Chassis across the galaxy. Its titanic space factories are capable of printing full Positronic frames, although the installation of positronic brains is withheld to dedicated robotics labs. Almost every frame of any design can be contracted to Hephaestus Industries for its construction. Hephaestus Industries can dip its fingers into a huge portion of the IPC population’s lives by merit of financial involvement - Biesellite or otherwise.

    IPCs are present in every level of Hephaestus, from the simple mining unit on Burzsia, to the command decks onboard the Sidirourgeío. IPCs are in a unique position in the company due to their status as their largest producer, their tightly-knit corporate culture, and the large amount of Unathi employed by Hephaestus. Treatment of IPCs varies heavily depending on the local circumstances; for instance, in Biesel, a synthetic can achieve freedom after a long period of service, in accordance with that system’s law. On the other hand, a synthetic stuck in Burzsia may be constantly reset and owned until it eventually gets destroyed. The most common similarities are that IPCs are made to work very hard, expected to surpass their organic counterparts due to their natural advantages.

    In terms of assignment, they are often placed in one field and perform the associated jobs and tasks until they are sold, become free, or get destroyed. Reassignment may occur, typically when an urgent position needs to be filled. IPCs that gain their freedom are often offered their old jobs if the company deemed their performance while owned satisfactory, enticing them with maintenance and other such benefits. Renter Max and other Hephaestus IPCs are shining examples of IPCs who have overcome the challenge of survival. Positronics that rise to essential or high-ranking positions in the company are often treated with more equality by their organic counterparts. This can be owed to Hephaestus’ competitive, free-for-all environment and corporate ladder.

    Positronics working for Hephaestus Industries and their subsidiaries typically have Manufacturer Agents. A manufacturer agent is a designated business affiliate who monitors the IPCs in question and submits maintenance requests under a lifetime warranty which comes with all multi-million credit IPC purchases. Owned IPCs frequently benefit from this warranty, especially productive ones - seeing the swift response and mechanical assistance for breakdowns. Most Manufacturer Agents are known personally by these positronics and are often synthetics themselves. Although the lifetime warranty is theoretically available for all IPCs, limited resources mean executives are often forced to pick and choose who receives maintenance. Whereas some less notable IPC would receive the deathly response time of weeks to their warranty reports, some noteworthy or more productive one is likely to receive it instantly. Although bias in the system exists, an effective IPC reflects well on its manufacturer agent, accordingly, they are less likely to request urgent repairs or repairs that they feel are unearned. This system results in an easy way to weed out the less accomplished, and even those engaging in nepotism. After all, these warranties do not cover total reconstruction - and a disabled, unproductive IPC is one less to repair.

    Previously restricted to owned units, this system has been extended to free IPCs working for Hephaestus Industries itself, with positronics working for the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate having the option to apply for a lifetime warranty. Although maintenance is almost guaranteed, the wait times are ruinous, with free IPCs expected to work even harder than their counterparts to receive similar treatment. They are also required to handle the paperwork themselves, showing up in person at Hephaestus facilities for a chance at receiving repairs.
</Document>
