<Document>
All Information included in this document is licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0, and is taken from https://wiki.aurorastation.org/index.php?title=Idris_Incorporated with some modifications

    # Idris Incorporated

    - [bold]Slogan:[/bold] [italic] Astronomical Figures. Unlimited Power[/italic]
    - [bold]Headquarters:[/bold] Abidjan, Ivory Coast, West African Union, Earth, Sol Alliance
    - [bold]Official Languages:[/bold] Tau-Ceti Basic, Tradeband
    - [bold]Official Colours:[/bold] [color=#3A6F6F]Teal (#3A6F6F)[/color], [color=#00d1d4]Cyan (#00d1d4)[/color], Black (#1e2221), [color=#E0F0F0]White (#E0F0F0)[/color]
    - [bold]Founded:[/bold] 2152 by the Standard Sol Calendar.
    - [bold]Founder:[/bold] William Idris
    - [bold]Notable Branches:[/bold] Celestial Cruises, Caishen Jewellers, Le Soleil Royal

    Idris Incorporated is an interstellar corporate bank headquartered in the Sol Alliance, though after the Solarian Collapse its branch in the Republic of Biesel has grown to become its most prominent base of operations. Representing the largest banking institution in the Orion Spur, they hold a practical monopoly over banking and financial services throughout human space. Idris financial advice is regarded by millions of businesses as something short of divine guidance, the bank able to predict, influence and even control the flow of stock markets in Sol and beyond, power frequently used to bend situations and create favourable openings. Since providing secure credit storage for individuals, corporations and governments alike require a robust security presence, Idris fields one of the largest private security forces spread throughout its vast number of facilities, vaults, banks and commercial establishments. To that end, a sizable synthetic division has been developed to reinforce and partake in various activities, most notably debt reclamation.

    Furthermore, the company manages a number of luxury product chains, hotels and high-class entertainment centres in a multitude of worlds across the Spur, expanding their clientele and becoming the go-to provider for powerful and influential elites of all calibres and tastes.

    ## History
    Idris Incorporated was founded in the Ivory Coast by the American-Ivorian investor William Idris in 2152, as pressure grew for a secure way to store credits and have them transferable across solar systems. Idris Trust was, at the time, one of the few banking institutions that offered interstellar services based in Sol, making them one of the most experimental, yet immensely convenient choices for business firms. Idris Trust was one of the first corporations to expand its base of operations to the extra-Solar colony of the Eridani Federation, contributing to a gradually-expanding trans-stellar range.

    Biesel's growing urbanization in the 2190s and beyond led to an increase in the personal wealth of its population. Many of these wealthy citizens were climate refugees from Earth, or high-ranking executives looking to carve out a piece of the newly-settled planet for themselves. NanoTrasen, Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals, and Necropolis Industries had cornered the markets on research and development, while Hephaestus Industries was a giant in the field of shipbuilding. But the migration of the wealthy elite and the relative lack of markets that catered to them led the Idris family to branch into luxury goods and customer service, purchasing several ship manufacturing contracts from Einstein Engines to create a fleet of luxury cruisers and yachts, and prepare their other vessels for shipping other products all over the known galaxy.

    Idris Trust rebranded to Idris Incorporated, meanwhile buying out or absorbing several smaller luxury brands into itself. Its new focuses made it a giant on Luna and Biesel. Through the power of branding, it quickly developed a reputation for legendarily thorough service courses that produced some of the finest chefs and mixologists in human space. All the while, every buyer was encouraged to use Idris banking, which spread across the Spur like wildfire and gave the megacorporation the title of the biggest bank in the known galaxy.

    Prior to the discovery of the positronic brain, Idris was one of the few corporations that eschewed simple robots to assist in service work. The company had managed to secure the loyalty (and fear) of many of its employees by luxurious paychecks or predatory loan contracts, and a point of its advertisement was that it relied on purely human service and no automation. But in the wake of the discovery of the positronic brain in 2407, Idris was one of the first megacorporations to adopt a line of "branded" IPCs, for security, service, and piloting. Still, the company is famed for its top-of-the-line human staff in the service sector, with many acclaimed chefs and mixologists to accompany the high brass on their business trips.

    In the modern day, Idris Incorporated is under the stewardship of the mysterious newcomer Alex Mason, acting as a member of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate. While Mason seems to hold the reins, the Idris family still hangs behind the scenes, directing the company at their inscrutable and often nonsensical whims.

    The bank has begun offering hiring bonuses to those who work for other major interstellar corporations to draw people away from their competitors. However, they are still in a struggle with NanoTrasen due to its large employee base mainly using the company's bank as their method of storing funds, preventing Idris from having a large number of members. This has strained relationships between NanoTrasen and Idris Incorporated, though the relationship between Alex Mason and Miranda Trasen is allegedly as sunny as ever.

    ## Influence and Reputation
    Idris Incorporated exercises authority over seven million major banks spread across human space and beyond, and has come to find itself in virtually every major power's pocket in some form or fashion. While not openly contesting NanoTrasen's net worth, Idris and its services can be found to extend as far as its looming superior can see.

    Idris possesses the financial information of nearly every human in the galaxy, and a significant amount of aliens as well. Because of this, it is an incredibly secretive corporation, and much of the information of its inner operations is behind NDAs given to every prospective employee. Idris employees are forbidden from even discussing their training, and there are rumours the company threatens or bribes those who speak negatively of the company's inner workings or management to keep the corporate image as spotless as possible. Employees who have proven themselves are often well-paid, and all Idris employees are well-trained.

    Behind the glossy, classy exterior, an "Idris loan" is almost universally understood to be a contract which it is incredibly difficult to break out of. Complex legal jargon and long terms of agreement are usually targeted at young, desperate, unfortunate, or all three; the few whispers of Idris' training programs point to them being harsh and exacting, with severe fines if one drops out early. This is to say nothing of the repute of Idris Security and Reclamation Units, who have stories floating around of causing broken bones and severe bruises to debtors.

    Any accusations of dubious conduct tends to fall apart or be settled out of court for ludicrous amounts of money. All the same, Idris' reputation preceeds it, meaning few would have the courage to stand against one of the most powerful megacorporations in the world... if they could find any evidence of it.

    ## Positronics and Idris Incorporated
    While Idris rarely permits free IPCs with exemplary histories to be recruited to their service department, the most common positronic presence in the corporate are the "brands" of owned synthetics that operate within the various departments of the company.

    Idris synthetics are usually dressed in the teal and black of the company uniform, and if Shells, are usually distinguishable as non-human by stylized "seams" in the synthetic skin on their face and decorative antennae. On some occasions, they are designed to physically fit in with the populace of the planet they are manufactured on or assigned to. Idris shells usually wear teal makeup, such as facepaint, lipstick, and eyeliner. The chassis colour of non-shell units ranges from cream, to teal, to black. Most commonly, they are programmed with high-class Lunan or Silversun expatriate accents. Organic Idris Incorporated employees in the same field as an Idris unit (for example, a guard to an IRU, or a cruise director to an IAU) are always considered as possessing seniority to the IPC, and are expected to obey the orders of organic personnel except when it directly conflicts with their self-preservation drive, or if it may cause undue loss to the company.

    Idris Incorporated security synthetics are perhaps the most notorious aspect of the corporation; they act as loan sharks and cold, uncompromising asset protection and reclamation units. There are two types of synthetic; Idris Reclamation Units and Idris Security Units. Both kinds are maintained by human handlers, who will often coordinate "departments" of security units. Hierarchy between reclamation and security units is often determined on a case by case basis by the units’ handlers. This ensures orderly and efficient management in environments where IPCs may be without the immediate oversight of their human superiors, such as if the units are shipped to another facility for a contract.

    Both reclamation and security units are carefully monitored by their human handlers and undergo regular check-ins. Uniformity and obedience is expected, where behavior outside the norm often results in loss of any autonomy they may have, or even wiping. Idris Security and Reclamation units are expected to wear the “Idris Unit coat” found in the Loadout under the Xenowear - IPC tab.

    Idris Reclamation Units are Shell frames constructed and programmed to investigate, interrogate, and reclaim securities or assets from a client in arrears. They are also employed for corporate investigative work and can carry out information-gathering on "problematic" or "at-risk" employees. In the interest of carrying out their various directives, Reclamation Units are granted authorization for the usage of "reasonable force" against clients, "reasonable" meaning never trending towards irreparable injury or death. They typically operate in teams of two units, who may have themed names and appearances. Reclamation units are designated by the prefix IRU-[Name].

    When security is needed for a VIP event or a vessel travelling into dangerous space, Idris Security Units are deployed. Security units are usually baseline or Hephaestus G2 models, though Shells and G1 models exist. These teams are accompanied by a human asset protection manager (who rarely engages directly with a threat), who will command the operation and make note of any lost assets or damages. IPC security teams consist of between 2-6 IPCs per human handler. Security units are designated by the prefix ISU-[Name].

    Given the sensitive nature of their field, security synthetics are barred from purchasing their freedom, and have their positronic brain wiped when they are sold. Many IRUs and ISUs are sold second hand or loaned out to various corporations who usually utilize them for security or investigation work.

    Almost all service sector Idris IPCs are Shell frames, though some baselines and Bishop frames exist as backline chefs or pilots. They fill a wide variety of roles within Idris' company sector, from acting as bank tellers, to piloting cruise ships and tourism vessels, to serving customers as chefs and bartenders. Idris service units are designated by the prefix IAU-[Name] if a pilot, and ICSU-[Name] if otherwise.

    While it is in theory possible for an Idris service unit to purchase their own freedom, depending on their current stationing, this is incredibly rare and difficult. IPCs stationed in places where their freedom may be purchased are closely watched, and will usually be cycled out at a regular pace or have their contract adjusted to prevent their own purchase with gathered funds.

</Document>
