<Document>
All Information included in this document is licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0, and is taken from https://wiki.aurorastation.org/index.php?title=NanoTrasen_Corporation with some modifications

    # NanoTrasen Incorporated

    - [bold]Slogan:[/bold] [italic] The leader in all things phoron![/italic]
    - [bold]Headquarters:[/bold] Mendell City, Biesel, Republic of Biesel
    - [bold]Official Languages:[/bold] Tau-Ceti Basic, Sol Common, Tradeband
    - [bold]Official Colours:[/bold] [color=#3d4f66]Navy blue (#3d4f66)[/color], Black (#282828), [color=#dfe4ed]White (#dfe4ed)[/color]
    - [bold]Founded:[/bold] 2366 by the Standard Sol Calendar.
    - [bold]Founder:[/bold] Xavier Trasen
    - [bold]Notable Branches:[/bold] Getmore Corporation, Hazel Electromotive, Ingi Usang Entertainment, Nexus Corporate Security, Five Points Armory.

    Considered the largest megacorporation within the Orion Spur, many will find themselves doing the biddings of NanoTrasen -- be it direct or indirect. Initially a biotechnical research company, it rapidly grew in size after the discovery of Phoron. The corporations monopoly on the resource catapulted it into the limelight, where it has remained for the last forty-odd years. Its acceleration into the spotlight has prompted many prying eyes to uncover evidence of rather questionable actions, with rumours perpetuating that they’ve instigated wars on both Adhomai and Moghes in an attempt to exploit the species for a profit.

    NanoTrasens power has since begun to waver as their ability to supply Phoron dwindled -- resulting in their profit margins diminishing considerably. Whilst the corporation has attempted its best to hide its waning influence, the facade has begun to crumble with scrutinizing individuals being able to see its vulnerability.

    Despite the effects of the Phoron Scarcity on the megacorporation, NanoTrasen has managed to secure itself as a crucial member of the newly-founded Stellar Corporate Conglomerate (SCC) with Miranda Trasen serving as the Acting Director of Operations -- which has managed to bolster the company and secure themselves as the dominant corporate presence within the Orion Spur.

    ## History
    Initially founded in 2366, the yet-to-be distinguished NanoTrasen was a small company revolving around genetic research and development on Mars. Xavier Trasen, Chief Executor of Operations for NanoTrasen (as well as its founder) managed to propel the fledgling corporation through the ranks after aggressively utilizing business tactics and effective patenting methods to buyout or destroy the local competition. By the end of the century, NanoTrasen had acquired enough capital to begin their operations on Biesel, even managing to secure mining rights in Tau Ceti.

    It wasnt until the discovery of Phoron in 2417 that NanoTrasen became a household name. The unearthing of the rosy crystals in the Romanovich Cloud, and the subsequent realization of its energy-producing potential, swiftly allowed for NanoTrasen to become a trans-stellar entity. Aggressively exploiting the new resources, as well as continued hostile business tactics, bolstered NanoTrasen’s position within Tau Ceti. Phoron’s capabilities made almost all other forms of travel obsolete, with the unveiling of the Bluespace Drive proving Warp to be slow, useless, and unprofitable in the face of this discovery.

    NanoTrasens newfound wealth was speedily employed to bankrupt, absorb or bribe their way to the top. NanoTrasens power and scope grew exponentially, with all types of assets (stations, facilities, ships) cropping up across the Orion Spur. Within the decade, NanoTrasen had managed to secure themselves as the most powerful megacorporation, with their influence felt almost anywhere.

    The declaration of independence by Biesel in 2452 has had a large impact on NanoTrasen, for the better that is. No longer under the purview or management of the Solarian Alliance, NanoTrasen capitalized on the planet’s vulnerability, successfully inserting themselves into the administration and its governance of the emerging republic. Whilst in recent times NanoTrasen has seen its influence wane slightly, they continue to reign supreme through tactical decisions and positionings. An example of such is its placement of their CEO Miranda Trasen as Acting Director of Operations for the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate.

    ## Influence
    NanoTrasen has managed to intrude on all aspects of life, with its apparatus and employees being found in almost every nation-state across the Orion Spur -- be it their manufacturing, research, or orbital facilities. It is almost impossible to not know what, or who, NanoTrasen is in this day and age. Its monopoly on the supply of Phoron within the greater Orion Spur has resulted in controversial behaviour, with NanoTrasen managing to successfully scheme and insert themselves within positions of power, through either bribery or direct buying-out of politicians that hold authority. The Republic of Biesel is a good example of these measures, where it is all but said that NanoTrasen controls the administration of the Republic.

    ## Internal Reputation
    NanoTrasen has managed to secure a variety of different work benefits for its employees, a common reason among many of the reasons for their employment with the megacorporation. These benefits go above and beyond the regular salary or wages and include insurance, flexible work schedules and other things. NanoTrasen further solidifies its increased work benefits through further education and training courses offered by the NanoTrasen Academy, with the only clause being to continue being employed at the megacorporation. Additionally, NanoTrasen also offers subsidised dental care.

    # Corporate Relations

    ## Einstein Engines
    NanoTrasen and Einstein have been rivals for decades, since the discovery of phoron in 2417 and the subsequent invention of the bluespace drive. As bluespace largely superseded warp as a means of faster-than-light travel, NanoTrasen's power rose as Einstein's waned. Since then, the two companies have been fierce competitors, contending in court constantly over various trademarks, patents, and other legal issues. The phoron scarcity beginning in 2462 has led to a reversal of fortunes, with Einstein rising massively in prominence as NanoTrasen's power fades - leading NanoTrasen to spearhead the formation of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate to attempt to combat their old rivals. The two corporations continue to clash to this day, with Einstein having found a foothold in the city of Phoenixport, Biesel - setting up shop in the heart of NanoTrasen's power. Though Einstein holds the clear advantage for now, NanoTrasen has worked tirelessly to try and slow the meteoric growth of their rival corporation - so far, to little effect, as phoron prices continue to rise and NanoTrasen stock prices continue to fall.

    ## Hephaestus Industries
    NanoTrasen and Hephaestus Industries have never been particularly fierce competitors, with the phoron giant purchasing much of its equipment, vessels and IPC workers from Hephaestus factories. However, as the phoron scarcity continues and NanoTrasen's power wanes, Hephaestus has taken full advantage of their decline. Since the formation of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate, Hephaestus has greatly expanded its presence in the Republic of Biesel, taking near-complete control of shipping on the moon of Valkyrie and moving its central headquarters to Mendell City. Hephaestus's expansion in the Izweski Hegemony - seizing a near-total monopoly of the kind NanoTrasen once held in Biesel - has allegedly been a source of great concern to NanoTrasen, who are rumored to be funding anti-Hegemony political movements on the planet Ouerea in order to weaken Hephaestus's position within the nation.

    ## Idris Incorporated
    NanoTrasen and Idris have never been fierce rivals, though Idris's continued prominence in Sol and its expansion into Biesel has led to tension between the two megacorporations. As Idris expanded its banking operations into NanoTrasen's center of power, NanoTrasen attempted to hold onto their banking business in Tau Ceti, incentivizing its employees to only make use of NanoTrasen banking instead - despite the many advantages that Idris held as a competitor. So far, Idris has been gradually expanding its presence in the Republic's financial sector, with many NanoTrasen employees switching to the use of Idris banks despite their employer's wishes. Idris has begun offering hiring bonuses to NanoTrasen employees in an effort to further weaken their power over Biesel's financial sector, as well as establishing branches in many of the former Solarian worlds of the Corporate Reconstruction Zone, where NanoTrasen holds much less direct influence. Though NanoTrasen has issued little official response to this, Idris transport vessels seem to commonly come under attack by pirates in the Reconstruction Zone, with many speculating the phoron giant is attempting to undermine confidence in Idris's renowned security.

    ## Orion Express
    NanoTrasen contributed the most resources to Orion Express's formation, and many of its executives are former NanoTrasen staff. As such, the relationship between the two companies has remained warm, with Orion taking over many NanoTrasen-held supply contracts across the Spur. Orion's continued operation in the Sol Alliance, and the fact that they continue to deal with Einstein Engines, has been a source of tension between the two megacorporations in recent years - but in spite of this, NanoTrasen and Orion continue to work together extensively across the Orion Spur. Though Orion's service industry has become a competitor to NanoTrasen's, this remains a small enough portion of both companies' business that it has not been a source of stress on the close relationship the two megacorporations share.

    ## Zavodskoi Interstellar
    Zavodskoi and NanoTrasen maintain a decent relationship, with little open conflict between the two corporations. Since the beginning of the phoron scarcity, however, Zavodskoi has taken full advantage of NanoTrasen's waning power in the Republic of Biesel, expanding its arms industry into the Republic. Since the formation of the Tau Ceti Armed Forces and the negotiation of several new supply contracts with Biesel's government, Zavodskoi has managed to take a great deal of business from NanoTrasen - seizing NT's position as the Republic's main weapons supplier. Though NanoTrasen still holds onto their original contract for the Tau Ceti Foreign Legion, the Minutemen and Republican Fleet are both almost entirely outfitted with Zavodskoi-made weapons, armor, and voidsuits. NanoTrasen has attempted to counteract this influence through the recent appointment of Nathan Trasen as Secretary of Defense - but even with a Trasen in such a prestigious position, Zavodskoi has still managed to secure a solid grasp on the Republic's military industry. NanoTrasen has increased funding to Nexus Corporate Security several times in an effort to use their newly-formed PMC to undermine Zavodskoi's security business in the Corporate Reconstruction Zone, with some measure of success.

    ## Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals
    Although NanoTrasen and Zeng-Hu work closely together, the two megacorporations have a rocky history. When NanoTrasen began, it was mainly operating in the biomedical field, which Zeng-Hu has historically been the frontrunner in - leading to NanoTrasen being outcompeted at seemingly every turn by the pharmaceutical giant. The discovery of phoron led to a rapid pivot in NanoTrasen's direction, and its many medicinal uses led to Zeng-Hu purchasing large quantities of phoron from NanoTrasen mining operations in the Romanovich Cloud. Despite this, Zeng-Hu CEO Liqin Hsiao-Li is rumored to still hold a grudge against NanoTrasen for their attempts to push into Zeng-Hu's sphere of influence decades ago, even as Zeng-Hu attempts to do the same in Biesel. Though NanoTrasen maintains its grasp on Tau Ceti's healthcare system, having blocked Zeng-Hu's expansions in the Republic's courts, Zeng-Hu has been increasingly expanding their operations in the wider Corporate Reconstruction Zone - having managed to seize the majority of the market share in the medical and pharmaceutical industries outside of Tau Ceti itself. Due to the many medical and pharmaceutical uses of phoron, Zeng-Hu remains one of NanoTrasen's largest purchasers of the increasingly rare element, and is reportedly one of NanoTrasen's closest allies within the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate.
</Document>
