<Document>
All Information included in this document is licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0, and is taken from https://wiki.aurorastation.org/index.php?title=Private_Military_Contracting_Group with some modifications

    # Private Military Contracting Group

    - [bold]Slogan:[/bold] [italic]Always on guard, always on watch.[/italic]
    - [bold]Headquarters:[/bold] Eridani III, Epsilon Eridani, Eridani Corporate Federation
    - [bold]Official Languages:[/bold] Tau-Ceti Basic, Sol Common, Tradeband
    - [bold]Official Colours:[/bold] [color=#b9bdcd]White (#b9bdcd)[/color], [color=#99ccff]Blue (#99ccff)[/color], [color=#3355ff]Dark Blue (#3355ff)[/color], Black (#363c43), [color=#c4a56e]Gold (#c4a56e)[/color]
    - [bold]Founded:[/bold] 2463 by the Standard Sol Calendar.
    - [bold]Founder:[/bold] Kubra Mobolaji
    - [bold]Notable Branches:[/bold] None: PMCG contracts for all members of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate.

    A coalition of security and medical contractors in service of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate, the Private Military Contracting Group is one of the elements born from the necessity of protecting an ever-growing corporate empire. Gathering mercenaries from all across the spur, the Private Military Contracting Group deploys a diverse force to anywhere they are needed; from mere office buildings to outposts in the Corporate Reconstruction Zone. As the megacorporations expand, these contractors follow to secure their holdings.

    Unlike the other members of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate, the Private Military Contracting Group has few employees of its own. Only some liaisons and bureaucrats work behind the scenes to hire and manage the contractors. The rest of its members are in fact part of several organizations contracted to supply the Private Military Contracting Group.

    ## History
    Eridanian military contractors as a whole originate in the early 2200s, during the takeover of the Epsilon Eridani by its economic council. As residents of Eridani I (then known as Kamfulu) rioted and unionised against dangerous working conditions, low pay, and environmental destruction that was occurring on the planet, the Eridani Economic Council formed two loose coalitions of those willing to "restore order"; citizen militias wishing to earn a paycheck in an unstable climate, and ex-Solarian military personnel who were used to pacifying an unhappy populace. These coalitions were deployed en-masse against protestors; they broke strikes, disappeared the loudest dissenters, and restored iron-fisted order to Kamfulu.

    After the majority of social unrest was quelled, these militias and private military contractors were gradually adopted into the new Eridani Corporate Federation. The experienced ex-military personnel were established as Ringspire, marketed as highly-paid, highly-deadly mercenaries capable of being deployed in conflict zones just about everywhere. Meanwhile, those who had started out with security contracting in the riots were organised into the less-formal Eagle Corp., who were eager to hire just about anyone and became a final option for the desperate all over Solarian space. These corporations would eventually fall under the umbrella of control for the Eridani Federation's chief of system security, essentially the commander-in-chief for any of Eridani's military forces.

    During the Interstellar War, these "EPMCs" grew to great renown as they were deployed alongside Solarian soldiers in ground forces and as strike teams alongside aerospace vessels. The news of their brutality was feared and loathed by the frontiersmen and Solarian allies alike. The Interstellar War also heralded the creation of Sekhmet Intergalactic in 2294, a medical contracting group; while Ringspire and Eagle Corp. had their own medical response divisions, Sekhmet's creation involved the recruitment of medical specialists, multi-pronged responses for both the groups, and an unscrupulous yet skilled and professional trauma response team to be sent out across the galaxy.

    N4NL Incorporated was the fourth corporation to join the official umbrella of Eridani contractors in 2307, as the group branched into data security, electronic warfare, and digital asset protection. While Eridani's mass surveillance and data collection algorithms had always been vast, N4NL perfected it, creating the intricate network behind the ECF's employment records, banking, and punishing Extranet surveillance. Shortly after its official addition, the collective of Ringspire, Eagle Corp., Sekhmet, and N4NL became known as the Golden Fist for their incredible reputation for quality results across the Spur.

    The corporation that would become the "thumb" of the Golden Fist was founded in 2450 by Farhad al-Sharif, a former N4NL executive and "positronic enthusiast" who had the unusual reputation of purchasing IPCs only to allow them to operate relatively uninhibited. Index Security Solutions was al-Sharif's plan to make better use of what he viewed as the fascinating capabilities of IPCs, and so became the only EPMC that recruited self-owned IPCs in large quantity.

    The Golden Fist's reputation was such that in 2463, in the face of the growing instability brought on by the phoron scarcity and the Solarian Collapse, the executive board of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate approached the Board of Five, Eridani's heads of government. The insurgency in the Corporate Reconstruction Zone had the Conglomerate envisioning an agency responsible for reinforcing the corporate security and medical ranks with hired contractors, in a similar fashion to how the Golden Fist was currently operated. It was proposed that Kubra Mobolaji, the chief of system security for the ECF, would be chief executive officer of this conglomerate within the conglomerate, and permit private contracting firms around the Spur to join the initiative.

    Thus, the Private Military Contracting Group was born, becoming an umbrella organization to coordinate several distinct contractor elements within the Conglomerate's structure. Its subsidiaries are tasked with providing adequate manpower, while the Private Military Contracting Group deploys them where it is necessary. While some may question the loyalty of the Group's employees, the credits fuelled into their contracts have been enough to secure their allegiance.

    The PMCG is currently tasked with supplementing the security and medical staff in SCC facilities, and was formerly tasked with supplementing the Tau Ceti Armed Forces during the Peacekeeper Mandate of Mictlan. When the megacorporation's lines become too thin due to the expansion of the conglomerate, the contractors from the Private Military Contracting Group are called to patch these holes. Despite their diverse backgrounds, all employees of the Group receive the necessary training to work in SCC facilities.

    ## Influence
    The PMCG has managed to carve out a niche for itself within the greater Stellar Corporate Conglomerate framework. Previously unknown or latent PMC groups are suddenly filling the holes that exist in the intricate networks of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate while drawing ire from some who may not wish to see the underworld of contractor work in their professional setting. It is not uncommon to see highly trained Eridani mercenaries flank loutish Frontier bounty hunters, or Unathite noble physicians among Tajaran pharmacists who have retired from biological warfare.

    Nevertheless, the Group's wide-ranging talents and Kubra Mobolaji's tight management, as well as being carried by the massively profitable Golden Fist, ensure its permanence as long as the PMCG's methods remain effective. They also hold power as an independent organization, always holding at least some influence in any war-torn region of space, including the Sparring Sea or the Solarian Wildlands, as they have grown quite popular among those who quickly need an expendable force to do their bidding.
</Document>
