<Document>
All Information included in this document is licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0, and is taken from https://wiki.aurorastation.org/index.php?title=Stellar_Corporate_Conglomerate with some modifications.

    # Stellar Corporate Conglomerate
    - [bold]Slogan:[/bold] [italic]The unbreakable chainlink, holding the Spur together[/italic]
    - [bold]Headquarters:[/bold]Top of the World, Biesel, Republic of Biesel
    - [bold]Official Languages:[/bold] Tau-Ceti Basic, Sol Common, Tradeband
    - [bold]Official Colours:[/bold] [color=#336699]Navy blue (#336699)[/color], [color=#81d9ee]Cyan (#81d9ee)[/color], [color=#f1b61c]Gold (#f1b61c)[/color]
    - [bold]Founded:[/bold] 2462 by the Standard Sol Calendar.
    - [bold]Founder:[/bold] NanoTrasen, Idris Incorporated, Hephaestus Industries, Zavodskoi Interstellar, Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals, Eridani Private Military Contractors.

    Formed at the height of corporate power in the galaxy, the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate — colloquially known as the “Chainlink” — is a group of seven megacorporations exercising undisputed economic dominance over the Orion Spur. The Chainlink was founded to secure corporate-owned assets within Tau Ceti during the invasion of the Republic of Biesel by Grand Admiral Raymond Özdemir, who commanded the 35th Fleet of the Solarian Navy during its siege of Tau Ceti.

    The Chainlink has essentially forced the largest economic influences into a shell corporation, which the Trasen family holds an unsteady authority over. Though cooperation has been deemed “essential” at this point in time, behind the shaky peace lies unsteady alliances, corporate espionage, and cut-throat tactics as each corporation battles for dominance. Their unlikely alliance comes as a result of Einstein Engines’ threat to their economic prowess, as Einstein's warp drives and prominence within the Nralakk Federation and Sol Alliance have given them a new edge in a galaxy affected by a phoron scarcity.

    [bold]Notable Members: [/bold]
    - Titanius Aeson, CEO of Hephaestus Industries
    - Alex Mason, CEO of Idris Incorporated
    - Liqin Hsiao-Li, CEO of Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals
    - Lyudmila Zavodskoi, CEO of Zavodskoi Interstellar
    - Kubra Mobolaji, CEO of the Private Military Contracting Group
    - Chin-hae Hong, CEO of Orion Express

    ## History
    Though once shrouded in secrecy, the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate has become a staple of the Orion Spur, acting as the masters of the interstellar economy. With the earliest dated supply shipments being traced to 2458, it appears that the constituent megacorporations within the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate have sought to cooperate with one another to ensure their economic dominance since the First Solarian Invasion of the Republic of Biesel, though within the shadows. Almost every element of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate had been hidden and concealed from the public, with even the deepest scrutiny only managing to uncover the "chainlink" insignia on supply shipments.

    However, following the Second Solarian Invasion of the Republic of Biesel in 2462, the cooperative of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate revealed themselves to the interstellar community, proclaiming their goal was to protect the financial livelihood of all their corporate clients and assets, and to ensure megacorporate facilities across the Republic of Biesel would not be diminished as a result of “rogue actors”.

    Since its reveal, the Chainlink has gone on to ensure its dominance through several masterful techniques – mostly centring around the Corporate Reconstruction Zone or the annexed Solarian territories by the Republic of Biesel. Pouring countless resources into stabilizing the region so as to further exploit it, the Chainlink has all but managed to prop the annexation as a legal undertaking of colonies abandoned by the Sol Alliance during the Collapse. Their efforts have not gone without resistance; in particular, the Republic of Mictlan proved ungrateful for the Chainlink’s efforts to uplift them. Sponsoring the Peacekeeper Mandate, a Biesellite military operation aiming to enforce the annexation, the Chainlink briefly managed to quell the uprising from various dissident groups. But the guerilla war on the planet has ended up in a less-than-ideal conclusion for the corporations, with Mictlan eventually securing both the surrender of its insurgents and the power to limit the megacorporations' influence.

    Meanwhile, one of the Chainlink's primary assets, the SCCV Horizon, has undertaken several humanitarian missions across the Spur in an attempt to bolster its reputation. Hephaestus Industries has helped provide the electronic "vaccine" for the Rampancy Crisis of early 2466, and at it and Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals' behest the Horizon has been assisting the Izweski Hegemony and the Nralakk Federation with humanitarian aid for the planet of Moghes.

    Elsewhere, the cold war and occasional skirmishes between the Republic of Elyra and the Empire of Dominia remain an excellent source of funding for both Zavodskoi Interstellar and the Private Military Contracting Group. The PMCG helps bankroll the Elyran military contractors of Jackal Incorporated, while Zavodskoi continues to manufacture and equip much of the Imperial Fleet. Yet both megacorporations do not directly rival each other, and both have goals of expanding into each other's home turf – it benefits both Zavodskoi and the PMCG to have as wide a client base as possible.

    Miranda Trasen maintains her dominance of the Orion Spur through her manoeuvring into the Director of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate, using her position to push NanoTrasen interests, to the annoyance of the other constituent megacorporations. Whether or not NanoTrasen can remain on top in the face of dwindling phoron resources and the refinement of Einstein Engines' warp drives remains to be seen.

    ## Influence and Reputation
    The sheer size of the co-operating corporations' influence is enough to sway many of the powers on the interstellar stage. While some of the larger political entities retain some measure of independence, they still ultimately rely on the constituent members of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate for their respective niches within the interstellar economy.

    Because of these galaxy-spanning ties, the SCC has promoted itself as a "peacekeeper" for the Orion Spur. Through the Conglomerate, nations and peoples that would have reason to make outright war with each other have settled on an uneasy peace – or, more cynically, a cold war instead of a hot one. The Stellar Corporate Conglomerate has leveraged the Republic of Biesel's independence from the Sol Alliance, and the corporate auxiliary forces of the Tau Ceti Armed Forces are a considerable contributor to the Biesellite military's staying power. Even the absence of a member-corporation from a nation-state is more space for the rest of the Conglomerate to form trade ties; the Republic of Elyra, despite expelling NanoTrasen from its borders, continues to trade with Biesel through Orion Express, Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals, and Idris Incorporated most prominently.

    From banks to manufacturers, only a sliver of economic productivity in the Spur is controlled by independents. The main threat to the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate is Einstein Engines; despite the combined power of the Chainlink, Einstein has managed to compete against them through tight ties with the Sol Alliance and Nralakk Federation, both the largest economies to exploit. But even despite this alleged rivalry, most of the member-corporations of the SCC have little trouble making dealings or working alongside Einstein Engines. Zeng-Hu and Idris are the most notable trade partners of Einstein, frequently purchasing their warp drives, their Shell frames, and commissioning them for ship designs, which causes the corporate echelons of NanoTrasen no end of grief.

    As the alliance grows older, it becomes more and more evident that the constituents are operating on their own agendas, with the Conglomerate an alliance of convenience. Conducting themselves in a manner to not directly oppose NanoTrasen, the other megacorporations have begun leveraging their economic influence on nations, as seen with Hephaestus Industries’ planned expansion across Moghes, Idris Incorporated’s leveraging credit provided to NanoTrasen during its attempt to recapture control of Phoenixport, and the Private Military Contracting Group purchasing the Grupo Amapola, made up of former corporate opponents.
</Document>
