<Document>
All Information included in this document is licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0, and is taken from https://wiki.aurorastation.org/index.php?title=Zavodskoi_Interstellar with some modifications.

    # Zavodskoi Interstellar
    - [bold]Slogan:[/bold] [italic]Even one matters on the battlefield.[/italic]
    - [bold]Headquarters:[/bold]Nova Luxembourg, Moroz, Empire of Dominia
    - [bold]Official Languages:[/bold] Tau-Ceti Basic, Sol Common, Tradeband
    - [bold]Official Colours:[/bold]Black (#363c43), [color=#637C65]Sage Green (#637C65)[/color], [color=#920a0a]Red (#920a0a)[/color], [color=#7a6347]Brown (#7a6347)[/color]
    - [bold]Founded:[/bold] 2259 (As Necropolis Industries), 2462 (As Zavodskoi Interstellar)
    - [bold]Founder:[/bold] Yefin Dementyev, Lyudmila Zavodskoi
    - [bold]Notable Branches:[/bold] Kumar Arms, Confiance Technologies, Ingkom, Falerio Security Services.

    Zavodskoi Interstellar, formerly Necropolis Industries, is a weapons and aerospace manufacturing and development conglomerate founded in 2259. Zavodskoi distributes everything from light to heavy arms, space vessel weapons, ship-building, aircraft, ground vehicles, combat spacesuits, and military software. They also produce the Z.I. line of positronics, used for private security and military contracting. As Necropolis Industries, it primarily focused on genetic research and the biosciences; though Zavodskoi continues to have a genetics division, it is vastly outstripped by its competitor Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals.

    Since the beginning of the phoron scarcity, Zavodskoi Interstellar has seen a rise in its relevance and profits, as civil unrest grows around the Orion Spur. Its focus on the research and development of weaponry has made it vital to the continued “stability” of the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate, as well as any other clients that have either purchased or hired their arms. Notably, its continued relationship with the Empire of Dominia has provided the Empire an opportunity for cooperative and profitable business relations with the rest of humanity.

    ## History
    Necropolis Industries was founded in 2259 by Yefim Dementyev, a former aerospace engineer with the Soviet Union. With the Alliance's outer territories beginning to show signs of unrest, the concerns of pan-galactic war were seen as an inevitability. With this in mind, Necropolis' making-a-splash invention was the combat-capable voidsuit. Lighter than a typical space suit and equipped with specialised atmospheric shielding that allowed a soldier to quickly slip in and out of it, the "Dracula" combat voidsuit was nevertheless heavy, cumbersome, and expensive. But the design showed promise, and the Sol Alliance's need for military expansion pushed demand for newer, sleeker versions, which skyrocketed with the outbreak of the Interstellar War.

    The years of the Interstellar War saw Dementyev oversee Necropolis branching into weapons and ship armaments, which were often purchased by the similarly-young and upcoming Eridani private military contractors. When the Treaty of Xansan was finally settled, Necropolis had secured a contract with the Solarian military, leading to it supplying the Alliance with guns and its now-iconic "Gargoyle" combat voidsuit.

    As relative peace followed the largest-scale conflict in human history, the board of directors turned their gaze to a yet-untouched (by them) field; biological experimentation. Though Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals was unambiguously more adept and well-established than their competitor, Necropolis' focus on gene therapy, xenobiology, and biological limb replacements led them to brief interest from the wider galactic community. While official correspondence pointed to a desire to broaden their sphere of influence and move away from solely weapons manufacturing, insiders at the company would later recount that Yefim Dementyev had begun to feel the creeping fear of his own mortality. Rumours would tell that he was obsessed with preserving himself and his legacy, and would use his own resources at any cost to achieve this preservation.

    However, Dementyev's pursuit was halted by his abrupt death from a septic infection in 2317. His son, Yevgeniy Dementyev, took hold of the company's reigns, and steered it into the twenty-fourth century. During this time, he would bear witness to the contact with the Empire of Dominia by the Alliance. Dementyev the younger quickly took advantage of the nascent Empire's newness to the galactic stage, and established relations with the Great Houses and Emperor Godwin Keeser himself. From then on, Necropolis and the Empire's intimate ties meant that Necropolis boosted the efforts of not just Dominia's conquest, but the efforts of its genetic modification.

    In 2389, Yevgeniy Dementyev passed down the mantle of chief executive officer to his son, Kasimir Boytsov. While Boytsov was not just a dabbler in genetics and had a keen mind like his father and grandfather, he was reputed for his impulsiveness and stubbornness, refusing to admit when the tides were turning against him. While Necropolis' developments in weapons manufacturing and genetics were profitable, they were being easily outstripped in the manner of shipbuilding by Hephaestus Industries, and left in the dust by Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals. By 2450 Necropolis had become the neglected runner-up of the megacorporations, the stocks of the other major corporate entities far outstripping them. But it was during this time that an information security operative at the company, Tikhon Zavodskoi, quietly recommended his cousin Lyudmila for a position as a weapons researcher. "The woman from Pluto", as she was known, quickly worked her way up the ranks of the company to become the assistant to the chief security officer, bringing in her own cohorts of associates from Dominia and Sol alike.

    2462 was when change would overwhelm Necropolis. Kasimir Boytsov was accused by the Alliance government of corruption, insider trading, bribery, and supplying the black market with weapons. He denied the accusations, but before a proper case could be brought against him, he collapsed at a press conference, and fell into a coma. The company was sent into turmoil; Boytsov had never named a proper successor, despite his rapidly-advancing age. Lyudmila Zavodskoi had become a surprise contender; her new group of executives, including her cousin Tikhon and the Imperial countess Kamilla Strelitz, pushed out the old heads and helped turn Necropolis into rebranded, rebuilt Zavodskoi Interstellar.

    Rather than pursue further genetics work, Zavodskoi Interstellar opted to pursue what it knew how to do better than any other megacorporation in the Orion Spur: military equipment. Three main pillars continue to drive Zavodskoi Interstellar. The largest is its classical military-industrial complex, and a massive amount of humanity's military equipment, ranging from infantry small arms to combat hardsuits to vehicles and much more, are today produced by it or one of its subsidiaries. Confiance Technologies, a recent subsidiary of Zavodskoi Interstellar, is one part of the military-industrial pillar that has even branched out into robotics. Its second pillar, as a result of Ingkom, is its robust engineering wing - Zavodskoi engineering staff are a common sight throughout the Orion Spur, though their usage within the Solarian Alliance has faltered following the Solarian Collapse of late 2462.

    A third, less public, pillar of Zavodskoi Interstellar is its private security force. These officers go wherever Zavodskoi employees go and are known throughout the Orion Spur for their professionalism. According to company representatives, Zavodskoi's security wing is one of the most competitive in the Orion Spur and is trained longer than any other megacorporation's security force. A recent turnover in the highest ranks of the security forces following the rebranding of Necropolis to Zavodskoi has caused some suspicion among third-party observers, but no information has been released on this by Zavodskoi representatives.

    ## Influence and Reputation
    As a hiring practice, Zavodski Interstellar finds itself poaching highly skilled workers from the other megacorporations. Workers with Zavodskoi usually flocked to the company to exploit its high pay - the dissolution of several underperforming departments and subsidiaries in more contested markets means that the company can focus and attract industry experts to work on weapons research. Although perfecting weapons of war is a task that will never truly be finished, the company is recognized as the uncontested leader in their development. As such, it holds a great deal of sway in almost every corner of the Spur.

    Clients ranging from small colonial militias to interstellar governments trust and rely on the megacorporation for their expertise. In this day and age, Zavodskoi pioneers where others do not by developing and manufacturing the highest-quality niche-function firearms, or just the biggest and baddest weapons they can muster. The extent of this research dominates every echelon of the corporation leading to the unified pursuit of maximizing the efficiency of its stock, rather than trying to cover the widest range possible.

    Zavodskoi Interstellar rarely works alongside Zeng-Hu contractors - intentionally so. The two corporations frequently butt heads after Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals left Zavodskoi genetics research in the dust, with the relation between the two sour at best. Although this attitude has lessened with the formation of the SCC, rivalry still occurs. This echoes down to the lowest ranks, as even the common worker can find themselves cheering onto outclassing the opposition. This isn’t an excuse to get fired for trashing your coworker.

    ## Positronics and Zavodskoi Interstellar
    In the aftermath of Necropolis Industries' rebranding into Zavodskoi Interstellar, synthetics and positronics have become more of a common sight in company facilities outside of the Empire of Dominia. These Zavodskoi IPCs are however banned from command and leadership positions within Zavodskoi Interstellar due to the corporation's internal policy, which views positronics as a workforce rather than a management force. This ban includes Zavodskoi Interstellar corporate liaisons.

    Newly implemented and with some in the company opposed to their presence, Zavodskoi positronics face systemic fragility within the company. In an effort to employ and contract out the best representation for the company, Zavodskoi will routinely memory wipe, retool, or outright scrap and sell their IPCs for workplace accidents, failure to execute an order, or underperformance. This process has been largely seen as a lighter version of the Burzian Method. This authority does not extend to Zavodskoi Interstellar corporate liaisons although they are encouraged to check in with their positronic contractor personnel from time to time. Therefore, Zavodskoi positronic contractors are often those struggling to maintain a positive evaluation or saved from the scrapyard all together.

    In an effort to bolster company morale, organic personnel are able to lease out Zavodskoi asset IPCs, should they so choose. This allows personnel to ‘own’ a positronic for the home without the burden of maintenance fees. For the IPCs affected, this can work to their benefit or their demise. As more lax personnel may feel less inclined to report aberrancy, whereas other synthetics would find themselves under greater scrutiny.

    Z.I. units are most commonly Shell frames and baseline units. Zeng-Hu Mobility and Bishop frames are uncommon, due to the rivalry between Zeng-Hu and Zavodskoi. Meanwhile, Hephaestus Industrial and Xion frames have some prominence within Ingkom and Kumar Arms, helping to engineer ships and weapons of war.

    [bold]It is expected for Zavodskoi Interstellar IPCs to adopt the prefix Z.I. followed by their designation. An example of this formatting is Z.I. Name.[/bold]
</Document>
