<Document>
All Information included in this document is licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0, and is taken from https://wiki.aurorastation.org/index.php?title=Zeng-Hu_Pharmaceuticals with some modifications.

    # Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals
    - [bold]Slogan:[/bold] [italic]Building a brighter future.[/italic]
    - [bold]Headquarters:[/bold] Shanghai, China, Earth, Sol Alliance
    - [bold]Official Languages:[/bold] Tau-Ceti Basic, Sol Common, Tradeband, Terran Mandarin
    - [bold]Official Colours:[/bold] [color=#a86bd8]Purple (#a86bd8)[/color], [color=#dfe4ed]White (#dfe4ed)[/color], [color=#b08fc8]Pink (#b08fc8)[/color]
    - [bold]Founded:[/bold] 2132
    - [bold]Founder:[/bold] Xihua Zhong
    - [bold]Notable Branches:[/bold] Bishop Cybernetics, Jeonshi Biotech Incorporated, Yomi Genetics Innovation and Research

    Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals is a trans-stellar medical research and pharmaceutical conglomerate with origins on 21st century Earth. They are responsible for the invention of modern cloning techniques, and have a hand in almost every form of medicine throughout the Orion Spur. Zeng-Hu has a unique internal structure referred to as the keiretsu by its employees: while officially known as a megacorporation Zeng-Hu is in reality made up of dozens of specialized medical corporations which build off of their mutual success, creating a structure most similar to a cartel.

    ## History
    The organization that would go on to become Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals in 2132 was born from the merging of nearly a dozen companies on Earth in the year 2032, creating a complete stranglehold over the medical field while avoiding traditional anti-trust laws. The keiretsu pioneered the way in the field of cryonics and cryogenics, manufacturing the first truly viable "cryopod" designed to safely house a human being during long-distance space travel. This proved instrumental during the colonization efforts of Mars and Luna, and would be used during further colonization efforts in the Solar System prior to the advent of widely-available warp travel. However, the success and profits the keiretsu derived from colonization was relatively short-lived, as the economic hardships of the mid-22nd century combined with the advent of proper warp travel -- which greatly reduced the need for their cryogenic storage units -- in 2130 hit the conglomerate hard. The hardships of the 2130s would shortly result in the formal founding of Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals in 2132, in an effort to stay profitable and keep component companies from being bankrupted and bought out by competitors. While never completely disappearing, it was overshadowed by the rise of other corporations edging in on the field of biotechnology and pharmaceuticals. Zeng-Hu stayed in the background for years, though their continual innovations and unique internal structure allowed them to stay competitive if mostly out of the eye of the public.

    It wasn't until the year 2332, when the Skrell were first encountered, that it was well and truly thrust back into the limelight. As with many other companies jockeying for positions from which they could benefit from the advanced technology of the Skrell, Zeng-Hu sent representatives to try and convince Skrellian scientists to establish joint cooperative research teams with their own scientists. However, unlike with the other corporations, whom most of the scientific community of the Skrell perceived as simply greedy, they were truly impressed by the vision and drive shown by the CEO Vanas Peng and his board of directors. After three years of cooperative research, the first viable example of limb cloning technology was created.

    Zeng-Hu was quick to patent the techniques and equipment and continued to advance in the newly created field of organ and limb cloning. While cloning technology was highly controversial when first introduced, it has since become an accepted and even promoted part of Human and Skrellian society. Attempts to bring it beyond the borders of these two species have not yet been widely pursued, with few in the keiretsu viewing such efforts as likely to be profitable or successful.

    Due to its collaboration with the Skrell and success in the biotechnical field of limb cloning, Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals is now among the most powerful trans-stellar corporations present in the galaxy in the modern-day despite its unusual structure. As its main competitor in the medical field, the NanoTrasen Corporation, continues to bleed profits due to the phoron shortage, Zeng-Hu has risen to fill much of what NanoTrasen left behind in the medical field. But despite the profits -- and influence -- it has gained from filling the market holes left by NanoTrasen the keiretsu has not ceased working alongside NanoTrasen, and many of their mutually beneficial research and commerce agreements have remained intact. Thus it did not surprise many economists to see that the keiretsu had opted to join with NanoTrasen in the Stellar Corporate Conglomerate, though some believe that the keiretsu is more interested with their own bottom lines than with whatever mission the ever-mysterious "Chainlink" may be dedicated to.

    ## Influence
    As the foremost medical service in the galaxy, overshadowing the former monopoly NanoTrasen once had over the speciality, Zeng-Hu's influence is immense. Their responsibility extends to the health and well-being of almost all citizens of the major galactic powers, with its constituent corporations delving into the pedantic of healthcare across the Orion Spur.

    Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals, and the majority of its minor subsidiaries, are professional science at its core. The public-facing sections of the megacorporation operate one of the larger public relations departments in the galaxy, a necessity for something as controversial as the primary healthcare provider. This reflects on employees as their workforce is encouraged to be plotting and outright secretive. In addition, the openly declared pursuit of Zeng-Hu has been the perfection of the sentient form and rapidly progressing what could be construed as the "expected evolution" of Humanity. The details of the future of this expectation are unfortunately classified, and guesses as to what the corporation plans are varied — from grounded to completely ridiculous conspiracies.

    Commercial contracting with Zeng-Hu is a cut-throat, careless business where decisions from completely untraceable elements within the corporation drift down to the lower ranks, usually deciding the course of lives. Workers take pride in their own capability to dodge the unknowable forces above, inadvertently, and the ideology has ended up fostering one of two things; either fear for one’s superiors or a dangerous lack of care. The latter in this environment rarely ends well.

    Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals rarely works alongside Zavodskoi contractors, and intentionally so. The two corporations frequently butt heads after Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals left Zavodskoi genetics research in the dust, with the relation between the two sours at best. This echoes down to the lowest ranks, as even the common worker can find themselves cheered on to beat the opposition. This isn’t an excuse to get fired by trashing your coworker.

    ## Culture of Augmentation
    Driven by a mad desire to reach perfection, the genetic and prosthetic modification of Zeng-Hu employees is prolific. High-ranking executives often loan prosthetics, augmentation and direct tickets to genemodding down to skilled subordinates, who in turn employ similar practices to their own. All the way down to the very field medics of Zeng-Hu echo a similar sentiment ; progressing in the company further perfects one’s form. Veterans can receive higher-end, more vast augmentation that broadly encompasses the body, though there are countless who opt to avoid these options.

    Augments to enhance one’s work are the most common choices here, providing a unique edge to an extremely competitive medical scene. Genetic modification, due to its expensive nature, remains uncommon, but many find themselves allured to the opportunities Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals has to gamble for this.

    These cases obviously have their downside where more expensive prosthesis, modding and whatnot are concerned. In these implements there are typically forms of tracking devices, ingrained serial numbers, limited licenses or some other binding force that marks it as property of Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals. Exclusive prosthetics utilized by the company’s employees very commonly have these.

    The reality of these measures result in heavily regulated augments - the more grim ones capable of being remotely controlled or even disabled by company officials freely. The exclusivity of these items are amplified further by Zeng-Hu’s ability to retract their loan - and ultimately reclaim possession of them for any reason. Authentic Zeng-Hu prostheses do have their benefits, as one is able to pursue various options that disability or plain Human inefficiency would never permit. From amplifying surgical precision to enhancing one’s endurance, there is a case for anything here.

    ## Positronics and Zeng-Hu Pharmaceuticals
    As the foremost company in the medical robotics and pharmaceutical industry, Zeng-hu Pharmaceuticals manufactures and employs a larger than average synthetic workforce. Aside from employing the machines in crucial and labor-saving roles, the corporation enjoys flaunting its latest models to the public, in effect using them as show dogs. IPCs which draw the eye of company managers and executives tend to be plucked from the ranks and elevated to positions of greater responsibility or authority.

    The company's treatment of IPCs is comparatively more egalitarian and less brutal. An overwhelming emphasis on perfection and unwavering quality is placed on the machines.

    Zeng-hu company projects often vary and as a result their dedicated synthetic workforce do not possess a standardized naming convention.
</Document>
